[Music]
all righty dude we're rolling happy New
Year Happy New Year is that what is that
response Yeah well yeah I've been
dealing with plumbing issues not sto for
the last week oh my gosh are you kidding
me what a way to start the hot water
heater then a then a sewer drain line
and yeah it's just not St fun oh you
dropped that's right you dropped that
chat in or the picture in the chat the
other day of literally like your bathtub
filled with sewer
water dude my wife she was like hey can
you come like look at this really quick
and I was like yeah I just like I
thought it was going to be something
simple and then just like that's
absorbed myre walked in there like hey I
Jo I don't think it's supposed to look
like this you know like it was like and
then I was like huh I was like trying to
debug it I like went into the garage
like go check it out turns out the
washing machine was running and cuz the
whole line was blocked the it was like
dumping water on the floor of the garage
there was like a half inch of water just
like sitting on the floor oh gosh it was
a mess it was a mess jeez dude that's
terrible well I I have had not the best
New Year either I have had a little
cold well you know so we all have our
our struggles right everyone has their
own problems they're struggling with
Joel um no that's hilarious all right
man um so here's what we're what we're
given to the people this week um me and
Joel and some of the wonderful listeners
uh some of the wonderful critical
thinkers subscribers to the Discord um
ctbb podcast Discord have put together
the best content of
2023 um for you listeners um we have
three primary sections we've divided
this up into we have technical content
from Justin and Joel we've got
interviews and then we've got sort of
bug stories so we've got about three
hours of content that we're going to
sort of recap and kind of put it in all
of this is oriented specifically towards
very technical content so it should be
very technically informative um so I'm
excited to get into it we'll just kind
of give you guys an intro to each one of
them as they come through so Joel is
that is that all we got to cover this
morning yeah I mean the only thing I'll
say is as you mentioned the ctbb Discord
that's uh we're doing a lot of really
awesome stuff the community is growing
lots of really cool research and
questions and tips and tricks and tools
and everything being posted in there so
if that sounds interesting to you go
ahead and check it out it's ctbb doow
Discord and that'll take you right to
the server invo the the server invite
link sweet dude first up on the list is
the technical content from Justin and
Joel section and and the first one is
episode 26 client side quirks and
browser hacks and in this segment we're
talking about exploding HTML injection
with meta tags and base tags anywhere in
the response body so hope you enjoy the
segment but yeah so the other thing that
I kind of want to mention and this was
actually sparked by a bug at a live
hacking event which you probably know
the one that I'm talking about um but uh
a friend of ours uh used a metat tag to
get a really really crazy bug at a live
hacking event um because he had an HTML
injection um and uh and so this is
something that I just kind of wanted to
make sure everyone was aware of because
whenever you have HTML injection it's it
feels kind of bad you know if you can't
get it to to xss but depending on the
context there's still a lot you can do
um and meta and base tags are two of the
primary tags that you can use to to
really do something cool
with yeah um I mean this cheat she cheat
is awesome there's a ton of cheat sheets
out there but I think you know
uh keep some of your own notes I think
is like the the key I would say because
like otherwise you're going to have a
folder that's got 50 different cheat
sheets that are bookmarked in it and
when you're trying to think of that one
thing you're G to have to click through
all of them to find them um but yeah
this is really really interesting I
didn't actually um I don't really F
fiddle with metat tags very much and I
think it's kind of underrated I like
early on like way back in the day like
metat tags used to be like a much easier
exploit scenario where you can just like
set like base URLs or something like
that that would allow you to exploit
them I don't know how much that's still
possible yeah not so the some of the
functionality because you used to be
able to I think trigger xss via um via a
meta tag and um according to this cheat
sheet it's still possible using a data
URI this was not something I got to test
before um the episode it says here that
it only works in Safari so I can't test
it right now Joel if you I don't know if
you got second most popular browser yeah
exactly seriously if you've got your you
know I don't know if you're on your Mac
right now but if you want to just throw
that little um you know data scheme into
the to Safari and see if it works then
go for it but um but meta essentially
has a bunch of functionality and one of
the cool attributes of it is this HTTP
equiv attribute and originally it was
designed to allow you to essentially set
HTTP headers inside of the the page like
sort of I guess sort of retroactively
because it's like you've already loaded
the body of the request um and I feel
like there's a lot more potential for
that um you know than than is possible
right now but um if you if you look at
this here let's see if I can pull up
this uh picture that I had in the in the
dock the current values that are
accessible for that are content security
policy content type default style and
refresh and each one of those are all
like pretty freaking interesting I think
um because with content security policy
you can trigger a Content security
policy to execute um inside the browser
using using that meta tag we see that
pretty often that's that's pretty common
um but setting the content type this
includes encoding that that's another
thing that I hadn't really thought about
before researching for this episode is
like you may be able to use the meta tag
to change the encoding for the content
body and Trigger some accss further down
in the page um if you've got some weird
injection points so that's one that I
had really thought about yeah so I just
tested this on on Safari um let's see
what version the latest ofar version
16.5.0
and what it does it throws an error so I
don't know if it's actually exploitable
or maybe you might need to do some
modifications but it does say not
allowed to navigate top frame to data
URL
colon text HTML so it does like it's
parsing it and it's like skipping over
that zero uh zero semicolon thing yeah
uh and it does seem to like try to do it
but maybe this is something that they
added recently um as as a fix um because
I know that like some of the things that
are in this cheat sheet are definitely
for older versions like it talks about
like Chrome 65 which is probably that's
way out there five five plus years old
yeah yeah for sure and and so like it
said there used to be a set cookie
instruction which is like oh my gosh
that would be lit old days that' be so
fun but the way that I see Meta tags
used most most um commonly now for
exploitation purposes is for this
content security policy stuff and then
also primarily for this redirection um
piece right because like think about it
it's very hard to get actually I can't
even really think of another way to ex
to redirect a page with no user
interaction with with just HTML without
using Javas script right yeah and and
for what it's worth that's that works on
Safari at least I just tested that like
the The Meta redirect through the
language tag like that works totally
fine but redirecting it to a data URL it
doesn't want to do yeah so you've
definitely got that in your pocket and
this can be useful in a bunch of
different scenarios um it can be useful
on embedded devices it can be useful um
in inside of headless browsers um and so
uh the open redirect piece you know by
The Meta tag is really cool and I would
love to see some research surrounding
um the content type piece um because I
feel like there's definitely some
interesting functionality there I was
trying to think about the default style
piece um I I couldn't really come up
with anything but it seems weird to me
so yeah so I mean there's always the the
scenario that always comes to mind with
like style stuff for me is the key like
the key press uh like sniffing where I I
think that's always been like a really
solid attack scenario where if you can
eject styles like you can either you can
create a really plausible fishing
scenario because you're on an SSL
assigned website that's looks completely
different and might have different
different content and stuff uh but you
can also do like key like key input like
changes where you like hit a background
like a background URL or something and I
think it still goes through some sort of
CSP right um but you know depending on
the scenario you can sniff keybinds
within the website purely through CS
says which is just like insane yeah I I
love I love that bug so much there's
been some really cool stuff with that
and I'm actually I'm looking at because
like W3 schools is a great resource and
I I use them all the time for yeah for
for you know this sort of thing but oh
yeah there's also whoa I'm I'm just
thinking about freaking out oh
okay geez you good can you hear me yeah
I'm back sorry it like totally went
crazy for just a second okay okay cool
um yeah so I I'm I was just thinking
about this right now like as we were
talking about CSS MH couple years ago
there was a pro a project that came out
called Doom Nukem CSS and it's a full
implementation of Doom that's written in
HTML and CSS no way and maybe it uses
typescript too I don't actually I don't
actually know but I'm pretty if I recall
correctly I could have sworn it was like
all CSS which was like
the craziest thing but it looks like
there's a decent amount of typescript in
here I might be wrong well G you know
Gareth Hayes you know we mentioned him a
couple times on this um on this episode
his personal website if you go to his
Twitter profile and you click his bio
link that's like a css-based like
freaking interactive game Masterpiece of
a website and it's just kind of like an
ongoing project for him and I'm like wow
that's like such a cool hobbyist
activity of like just mastering CSS
stuff and he and he tweets about like
CSS related quirks all the time which I
think is really helpful as well yeah
what is it Gareth hay. co.uk yeah check
it out oh man this while you're checking
out I wanted to this is exactly what I
was thinking of actually yeah yeah yeah
so there's some really crazy stuff you
can do with CSS um with just pure CSS
which is nuts but um I what I was going
to say before my computer started losing
its mind um was that I went to W3
schools and I was it says that there's
only four attributes that can go inside
of or values that can go inside of the
HTTP equiv um header I mean html
attribute um but actually I'm looking at
some other stuff and I think there's
more so like I've seen other references
to window. Target and content and coding
as well so I'm actually after this
episode I'm going to go try to sus that
out because um I think there might be
some other things we can put in HTTP
equiv that could really really mess with
the you know the Dom um that's being
loaded up so definitely some cool stuff
Wonder there's like
undocumented features and like
functionality because I feel like a lot
of browsers will
create just like they'll create weird
edge cases with like that they use
internally um that are only really
designed to be used by them that may not
adhere directly to the HDML spec or what
the public spec says should be possible
but is actually still possible and you
know it's important to remember that
just because the spec says that it
should be this way doesn't mean that
it's actually implemented that way for
sure yeah yeah there's definitely some
some I'm looking through right now
there's some weird some weird stuff
there so I'm going to check that out
afterwards um but for for those of you
listening right now what we can what we
can confirm right here is it's it is
helpful for exploitation in a Content
security policy scenario if you want to
make the content security policy
stricter to lock out like for example a
um like for example if they're loading
up a a JS library that does purification
or something like that then it's helpful
there and then it's also possible to use
it for a a no additional click redirect
if you have an HTML injection so that's
helpful as well yeah yeah super cool um
so the other thing that we were going to
talk about here was the base tags um and
base tags this is something that that I
didn't know about till recently I think
these have to be in inside the head um
uh sort of section W within the browser
um or within the Dom so I'm not sure how
often we're getting injections up in
there um but yeah the there's some
really cool stuff you can do with this
um essentially it allows you to turn
relative URLs into uh you know fully
qualified URLs with your domain which is
super helpful for um you know hijacking
stuff further down in the flow of the
page uh and and maybe even bypassing CSP
in some scenarios um I get some I don't
know if you can nonon external import
but um yeah that would be that would be
helpful in that scenario yeah I'm just
testing this one on Safari as well just
to double check because I'm pretty sure
you're right that it has to be almost
certain it has to be in the in the head
yeah yeah I think I think it has to be
um uh but yeah I I didn't know about
this and this is just another really
cool piece that you can you can use in
HTML injection it doesn't it doesn't
have to be in the head what maybe Safar
is doing something weird yeah this could
be something that is do doing weird but
I did just double check and in my body
element I put a base hre and a script
tag and it is trying to load it from the
base hero wow that's in the body tag I
stand corrected man yeah this this has a
lot of power this element um and HTML
like we mentioned HTML injections can be
kind of tricky but this is definitely
something that you can use to kind of
try to turn the tides in your favor
headers Chrome is doing it too I've ner
sniped Joel is just like staring wide at
his at his computer right now like
Chrome does it too so yeah if you put
the base tag the that up yeah dude I I
could have sworn that it was a head only
thing yeah but okay yeah so a base uh
base tag anywhere um will change where
it tries to load from even if it's in
the body very solid man all right next
up we've got a clip from episode 27 this
is where we were talking about esoteric
web vulnerabilities and this one
specifically is talking about about
client side path reversals this is very
interesting bug from Jus I was I was
talking about client side path reversals
you were talking about secondary context
path reversals um but we got the we got
the conversation done either way so hope
you guys enjoy this one um next one that
I had on the list was client side path
traversal now this one's a little bit
weird because you think of path
traversal normally as a you know server
side sort of thing you're you're putting
something in either a query parameter or
a path um and directly in your URL and
you're getting to access to some path
that you that you didn't previously have
access to by using some iteration of do
do slash or combination of dot do
slashes right um client side path
traversal occurs when you are able to
inject via a query parameter or a hash
or something in the user's browser so
you know the users clicked the link or
you've redirected the user to a specific
spot um and that page is uh loading a
resource based off of your attacker
based input so let's say for example you
redirect them to google.com example1 234
and they try to load a CSS page that
that's like css12 34. CSS right so your
1234 from the path is being taken and
put into a resource that's being loaded
then you know if it's URL decoding it
and stuff like that you can try to use
some um path traversal sequences to hit
a different part of the application
hopefully hit a redirect and get
yourself a full CSS injection on that
page which as as we all know from
listening to other episodes of critical
thinking can result in some very
critical stuff um so uh that's sort of
what I had on client side path traval
you got any other thoughts on that Joel
yeah I mean this isn't a client side
path traversal but I think one of the
things that's kind of closely related to
this that I really like as a class of
bug and this is kind of it's not really
talked about a ton but I think it it's
like path reversal through ID and often
times I see this with like there's a
post request that includes an ID in it
for example there say it's a posting a
Json body one of the parameters is ID in
the body and it's a uyu ID or something
well often times you can put uuid SL do
do slash some other arbitrary path some
arbitrary internal path or something and
that just gets fully concatenated into
an internal request and it's it's like
in the line of ssrf kind of srf paath
reversal but it's a really really
interesting technique and I see it
exploited all the time like all over the
place it's something that I now
regularly check for whenever I see an ID
being sent is let me just try putting a
dot dot slash and then like the same ID
after it and just see if that still
works because that's often a really good
indicator of whether or not it's working
and that's kind of um I don't know it's
it's not quite esoteric it's it's a
little more common but it's like a weird
um route for exploiting like RFS and
kind of a server side path traversal if
you want to call it that um and I think
it it it deserves being mentioned
alongside this yeah for sure man I I've
seen those all the time and excuse me
they're very impactful bugs if you can
get them to work especially if you
understand what API is being hit in the
back end or you have some introspection
to that through the error or something
like that those are some crazy crazy
bugs so and and then just to clarify the
reason why you're saying put so let's
say we've got ID or U ID equals you know
1 2 34 D what whatever then you put a
slash at the end you put a dot dot slash
right so that would delete the ID you
just put in right Y and then you put the
same ID again so that that path is
should be normalizing to the same thing
it was without having the any of the
path traversals in there right right and
you can imagine this in in the backend
scenario is basically like one service
is hitting another service the way it
does that yeah yeah microservices
hitting through an HTTP request and it
goes you know other internal service.
host
slid or whatever SL API getet slid or
something right however you want to
imagine how it's being put in there and
then if you're giving it a full value
and it's not being sanitized and that's
just being chucked onto the end of that
URL your path reversal is going to
affect that internal microservice call
and be able to hit other API endpoints
and other things within that other
service that you may not have been
intended to to hit and I I see so much
impact approved from these all the time
it's really insane some of the biggest
uh baddest vulnerabilities I've ever
seen are caused by this and it's
something that seems so simple and
straightforward so if you're not
checking for that be sure to check for
that because it's it's again it's it's
not quite an easy win but it it's it's
it definitely gives you a lot of
Leverage yeah and I think it's systemic
on the targets as well normally because
the target is using a microservices b
based architecture so if you find one
you're likely to find lots of other
unique issues as well with their own
unique fixes um and so I'll actually
also Link in the in the notes for this
episode um that uh there's a blog post
by Sam Curry and I uh that did let's see
when did we I'm not sure this is a long
time ago that we had done this I mean
Sam is like the king of this type of
he's the one who I like learned it off
of and I see so many crazy impactful
bugs that are that are shown by him
using this uh I I wasn't sure which ones
I I should even talk about because I
know like some of them are not public so
yeah the Starbucks you have a good
example have the link it's public
there's a blog post so we'll link it in
the description if you haven't seen it
that's great but um Joel you we we we
got off topic there the one that I'm
trying to talk about here is the client
side path reversal which is different
very notedly different so don't very
notedly different yes um this is
something that happens in the users
browser I mentioned this happens in
stylesheets but it also happens in JS
files and it can also happen just in in
Fetch and Ajax requests right so
requests that are being sent by the page
via JavaScript and those are very
impactful as well because if you can
Traverse in a context where it's trying
to like let's say it's sending a post
request to like you know load your news
feed or whatever right if you can
control that path and you can hit it you
know make it hit like SL delete account
and that delete account doesn't require
any you know parameters then you can
force user to just delete their account
I've found this bug before um and so
definitely be on the lookout there's a
lot of different implications it can
result in um CSS injection it can result
in xss it can result in um this sort of
C surf sort of outcome um and then the
other thing that I I I don't know how
much of an issue this still is but um
there used to be this thing called 401
injection where you can inject a uh you
know a prompt where it would pop up and
it would ask the to type in their
credentials right and then that prompt
was actually coming from your website
but it was on the page that uh you know
you injected into um that used to be a
bug I don't I I didn't get the chance to
check it before this episode to see
whether it's still active or not but um
if that could also be a potential
outcome from this sort of a client side
path traversal if you can find an open
redirect and redirect to your own site
where you serve a 401 yeah I do wonder
if that's still a thing I I remember
that that class of vulnerability but I
don't actually know know if it's still
accessible that's that's with like uh
realm like authentication stuff right
yeah yeah and and I'm I'm pretty
confident it's it's possible in at least
one of the major browsers I just can't
remember which one it is so we'll have
to check that out I've got some good
guesses and it's probably not Chrome
yeah it's definitely not
Chrome sweet next up from also from
episode 27 is Cookie bombing and cookie
jar overflows this is some really
helpful content surrounding using
cookies to assist in exploitation chains
all right next one cookie bombing have
you have you heard of have you heard of
cookie bombing do you do cookie bombing
Joel I before I get put on the list here
uh so I I hadn't really I the I'd heard
of the name and I understand like the
concept um but until I actually read
through file the scriptures um slides
about this specifically now it it
definitely clicks and I would kind of
tie it in with the next one that we were
going to talk about which is cookie jar
overflow but basically these two classes
are um exploiting just like sort of
native browser Behavior around how
cookies are set and sent and so
oftentimes there have been new security
features that have been added to like
how cookies work for example HTP only um
or site secure or whatever um and that
make it so that they're only accessible
within certain contexts and they're only
sent within certain contexts and you
know if it's HTTP only then your
JavaScript can't read and write it but
that's fine because sometimes you
control a web server that is doing that
over HTTP instead of doing that over
JavaScript and so with cookie bombing
for example you can set multiple cookies
for the same host on different paths and
when they get sent the browser doesn't
distinguish whether or not you know
oftentimes well maybe it does I mean I
mean it's supposed to the paths the
paths piece um you can use the different
paths to bomb specific endpoints so like
you said you know the the this is
abusing a sort of browser level problem
with cookie management which is if you
send too many cookies uh the browser
will still send them to the to the
server but the server will sort of I
guess this is sort of a serers side
issue then the server is going to freak
out and be like okay whoa whoa whoa this
request is way too big please please
stop right and it's gonna I forget what
status code it sends it's it's some 400
status code um but it it freaks out and
it doesn't like that right um and so you
can set you know you can set enough
cookies that the browser will happily
send along which essentially dosses your
access to a specific website until you
delete your cookies right um and you
literally do that just by setting all
right cookie one equals 99,999 A's
cookie 2 equals 99,999 A's you know and
then like do that until you've blown up
the whole request right and um and that
will result in the what whatever users
browser you're you're setting this in uh
not being able to access the Target the
Target website until they clear their
cookies um and this can be particularly
tricky here's here's a here's a fun one
here if you do this on a sub part of a
website that is not the top URL because
what what people will do sometimes is
they can't access the website they'll
delete the cookies for the specific
website that they're on right which is
their top URL but let's say for example
you Cookie bombed the api. domain right
the API ..com the that's never in the
user's top level browser so if they try
to delete their cookies for that website
then they can't do it right without
without going in there and actually
deleting all of their cookies which is
kind of a pain in the ass because it it
logs you out of literally every single
website yeah um so this is this is a
really cool V and you can do this with
just a gadget that sets allows you to
inject a cookie on the website which is
fairly common um and this is also a
great way for you to um show uh an
effect to availability uh which up your
CVSs score um and it really helps with
like stuff like subdomain takeovers to
show impact yeah yeah there's actually a
cool tool idea I just thought of right
now as we were saying that which would
be something that basically you could
plug in your existing CVSs score or
maybe like say you have a bug and it
meets certain criteria within CVSs and
then the tool would tell you if you
could get the if you could change this
one Factory it would take your bug from
a medium to a high or a medium to a crit
or something that's a great idea so so
have you could put in your CVSs score
and then it'll tell you okay your
easiest escalations are going to be all
right if you can figure out how to
affect availability just a little bit
you know maybe try cookie bombing or
something like that dude that's a great
idea someone's got to build that yeah
yeah uh not us though yeah I got too
much going on yeah CR critical thinking
Community please please take that and
run somebody make that to even if it
takes four years bit workk Yeah at bit
work uh no that's great um and the the
other thing that I was going to say um
specifically on appcash I mean um on cie
bombing is you can use it with stuff as
well like like appcache um because
what'll happen if you define an app cach
on a specific page uh if there's an
error that occurs at the browser level
uh it it will sub in a different content
so it's perfect for cookie bombing and
I've seen this I've seen frons abuse
this I've seen file descriptor um use
this and he actually mentions it in his
talk entitled The Cookie Monster in your
browsers which I think was the talk were
mentioning earlier um and he also
mentions how you can use it to get it to
not consume ooth tokens cuz you can
cookie bomb the specific ooth endpoint
right such an interesting attack Vector
so yeah I guess if you basically cookie
bomb and it sets too many cookies the
request will fail but the request the
outbound request will still contain like
the credentials or whatever in the URL
and so you can because it's like a
failed Quest it doesn't hit like iframe
options I guess is that correct well so
there there's some there's some
intricacies like that but the one the
one that's really you know help helpful
in this scenario is like and it can help
you avoid iframe options and some CSP
stuff as well but in a scenario you
you're when as soon as that that code
lands on the page where the call back is
it gets used and consumed right so even
if you have a reference to that window
and with an xss or something the like
you can't consume you can't get to that
token in time because it's gonna you're
going to lose the race every time and
it's going to consume the off token and
you can't get account takeover but if
you Cookie bomb the endpoint where that
oo code is getting returned to when it
goes to that page it's G to fail but you
because your same origin you can still
reach into that page grab the you know
um window location.href and pull the
code out of there which would allow you
to get escalate your xss to atto it's
just such a such a great technique I
love it yeah that's awesome yeah yeah um
on cookie so then like tendential that
the cookie jar overflow which is kind of
similar in like sending too many cookies
or like sort of overflowing how the
browser is behaving but you actually
have a whole tool for this which I did
not know about called check cookie jar
overflow I I don't know what it's what
what you call it but it's a link on your
on your domain it's a link apps. renator
dodev you guys can check it out this is
just kind of it's just kind of like if
you click on it it's kind of like just a
SCP Cy little website with like a
freaking um Apache you know index it's
literally 20 20 lines of htl including
the script and essentially um what it
allow so actually before prepping for
this episode I was like all right let me
you know I was prefer this episode I'm
like you know right all right I'm going
to drop some knowledge I'm G to you know
show them all these cool like weird
esoteric web vones and then I get in
there and I and I was researching for
cookie bombing and I find this cookie
jar overflow thing and I'm like what the
heck is that I've never even heard of
that and so I found it and I think it
was on the site hacker yeah hack tricks.
which is really cool like that's a great
website by the way um yeah did we talk
about this last episode too we might
have
but yeah I think did but again this is
like one of those like informational
type documentation websites that we
talked about where this type of resource
is something that like keep it in your
bookmarks and just like if you're ever
stuck on something check all of the ones
that you have bookmarked because
be like weird Edge stuff or just like
interesting techniques that somebody has
documented somewhere that you can take
advantage of to escalate your
vulnerability to the next level yeah
there's so many awesome like just weird
things in this hack tricks.xyz um
website so I'll do my best to sort of go
in and and digest some of that and and
put it up back into the podcast um in an
auditory format but when I was prepping
for the the like was for the cookie
bombing I ran across this cook jar
overflow which is really cool and I
actually um had I known about this um at
the last live hacking event I would have
been able to save a friend a lot of time
because he had to go uh down this this
path to get rid of this cookie that he
needed to be gone um and uh he could
have just used this technique um and it
would have just he would have been able
to get it gone in just a second so the
technique just to be clear is um you
essentially just set a bunch of cookies
in the browser for a specific domain and
each domain has a limit on how many
cookies can be associated with it in the
browser that's the cookie jar and the
cookie jar limit um and so if you if you
exceed that limit cookies start getting
deleted oldest first so you can Edge out
the other cookies in the user's browser
even if you don't know the name of that
cookie so let's say for example you have
a cookie um you know session uh off
session XYZ random string equals
whatever the session token is right you
don't know what that random string is so
you can't overwrite that cookie and if
it's an HTP only cookie you can't access
it from the JavaScript side even if you
can set cookies right so you need that
cookie gone so you can do a session
fixation um and how do you how are you
going to get rid of it because you don't
know the name of it right so um this is
a cool technique that you can use to do
that by setting a bunch of cookies
overflowing the cookie jar and then
being able to use your own values um and
one of the things that I thought was
really interesting is you can Edge out
HTTP only cookies even from a non-http
only contact which I think is really
cool and seems like a little bit of an
issue right yeah well I mean and again
this is like weird Behavior that's kind
of intended but also not intended like
you know it it abuses like one two
functionalities that both need to exist
at the same time and they kind of
collide with each other tangentially
right where it's like HTTP only
shouldn't be able to be set by
JavaScript but if you set a bunch of
other cookies with JavaScript eventually
you'll have too many cookies and the HTP
only cookies will just get removed and
like yeah you know that what the browser
is going to just have infinite memory no
like you can't right so like these two
things have to both exist and there's no
real easy compromise there so it's super
super interesting behavior and one of
those things that you know have it
documented keep it in the back of your
brain and then when you need it you'll
have it yeah for sure so we'll add some
links down below the little um sort of
tool that I that you mentioned before
that you saw in the dock that was just
something that I sort of scrape together
to help people understand where their
cookie jar overflow limit is in the
browser so you guys can check it out
we'll link it down below it's apps. rat.
dcookie
orche cookie jar overflow HTML in camel
case of course so you know probably
easier to just click the link you're
welcome just click the link in the
description um but essentially if you go
to that and you click on it it will set
a bunch of cookies and tell you where
your cookie jar limit is in your browser
um I ran it in Chrome in prep for this
episode and it puts it at 180 cookies um
the range for this is between I think
150 to 180 but every time I've run it
I've gotten 180 so um you know you
should be able to do it pretty easily
yeah and maybe as some off off the Pod
research I would be curious if this
matters more uh like the length of the
cookie if that matters at all or if it's
just purely number of cookies do you
know I think it's just pure number of
cookies because I was just sting let me
take a look at the code really quickly
here you say off the Pod research and
then you know we're going to do it right
away yeah we're going to look right now
yeah no it it's just it's just you know
check and then the index equals the
index so I'm just saying check one
equals one check two equals two and that
sort of thing and it's overflowing at
180 so I think I think it's just a
number of cookies thing all right this
next clip from episode 44 is really from
a l takeaway episode but there's some
really cool tips and tricks in here
specific specifically around cross
environment authentication spe
specifically how you can use
authentication tokens from one
environment on another environment
potentially get access and bypass all
sorts of access controls I just also
wanted to talk about some other Concepts
that have kind of been banging around in
my head from the live hacking events
that we've been to over the past couple
months um and you know there's just been
lots of good discussions with hackers
and and one of the ones that that came
into my my brain was this concept of
shared Secrets across environment ments
you know um and specifically JWT related
things um if you have a a JWT signing
secrets that's shared across multiple
environments and you're giving people
you're allowing people to register on
one environment with an email and then
you can use that same token because it
passes validation on a different app you
know I have no idea what you're talking
about right now I've never seen that
exact I've never seen that exact bug uh
on a oh really tet well I was talking to
someone specific about this sort of bug
um you know at at a live hacking event
but yeah essentially the bug was that
you know there was a stage environment
you could sign up for you'd get a JWT
you could use that same JWT on the prod
environment um so let's say you've got
an account registered you know Joel
jo.com right I could go to the staging
environment register joel. jo.com you
know if there's not email I am being
sarcastic right now because there was I
I don't know if you're like playing in
on this but yes there was this exact
same thing on
it wasn't staging but it was just that
you could like log into certain apps and
then any app within that same like they
use the same off mechanism like
middleware or whatever across all their
things yeah you see it you know you see
it at at on various targets uh you know
I wasn't I mean what was that sarcasm
was that like are you saying because it
exists because that was almost the exact
bug that I was just talking about as
well with stuff it was the same Target
and it was utilizing that bug what the
heck I did not hear about this this is
crazy okay I didn't yeah yeah yeah so
there was an off by to get into one of
these tools yeah this is more prevalent
than expected I think because this is
this is you know multiple live hacking
events over the past year that that has
had you know this issue pop up on a
Harden Target like a Live Hack event
Target so definitely something we see
and would was sort of on my radar
because we talked about Cookie Monster
in the past right that uses sort of um
you know that kind of has a similar
situation where it's like okay you know
maybe you can forge this JWT but reuse
of that JWT wasn't really on my radar
until this past year quite as much yeah
and honestly like from a from an
engineering perspective I totally see
why it's happening because there's more
and more push to centralize all these
sorts of off mechanisms into one place
and have like a single single mechanism
that's doing all the authentication in a
standardized way which means that you
have more risk for somebody to be able
to issue an off token that's just valid
unless that single Central off mechanism
is really really strictly properly
checking like where did this come from
is it specifically authorized for this
other application that they're trying to
use it on more than is it valid and is
it like validly signed and all that kind
of stuff because all that stuff could be
true but it could be for some other
service and it could still pass it's
actually similar to the uh to the thing
we were just talking about uh you know
before when when you're reusing tokens
across different different providers too
right like the the Facebook thing where
where they're not checking the app ID
associated with it right um because it's
actually a token for a different
provider but you know it kind of all
checks out so uh there there's there's
definitely reoccurring themes that we
see across these authentication bugs
which the more and more you familiarize
yourself with them you'll you'll start
looking for those uh attack vectors
which that's been kind of a way I've
I've grown as a hacker over the past
couple years is like um authentication
related bugs can be really scary and
sometimes I feel like I'm forced down
that route because the other scope is so
[__] you know it's like all right might
as well just look it off and then when
you do some crazy bugs can come out of
that so yeah and it's weird because like
I almost never look at off a lot of the
time because it's such a weird it's such
a weird flow and you can end up sinking
a lot of time there yeah and it's like a
lot of times it's like a weird setup
stage where there's very like limited
restricted amount of data and the
program even if you submit it they'll be
like oh well this is just the
registration flows so unless the impact
is like elsewhere within the application
oftentimes it doesn't even like really
count or it's not a high enough impact
um but yeah like you said when you get
backed into those Corners where where
it's a tight scope I mean we just saw at
the last event lots of off stuff that
was just like you know small scope where
do you look but you know you you also
look at the at the hackers that pop
crits on a regular basis right you look
at Sam herb you look at oacb you look at
some of of these guys that make a habit
of looking at o every single
time they they always pop stuff man they
always and so um yeah that's something
that I've sort of resolved to look into
a little bit more um and and on that you
know on that note uh I I was going to
talk a little bit about um one of the uh
sort of successes I've had in this Arena
which is um uh finding or I guess
looking at o which is multiactor
authentic bypasses and there's lots of
like you know super crappy multifactor
authentication bypasses where you can
like just navigate to the page or like
you know there's some some some um you
know other tricks you can do but one of
the things that I kind of wanted to
highlight is like especially when you've
got a flow where there's multiple mult
you know multiactor devices like hey you
know do I want to send a text message to
the phone or do I want to get an email
or do I want to get a push you know
these systems get really complex and
these OB objects these um devices
they're just objects in the application
and they're vulnerable to stuff like
idor just like every other object in the
in the application could be right so um
you know I remember taking a deep dive
at a target one time and and kind of um
looking at this flow and finding an idor
in the multiactor authentication flow
it's just allowed me to use an attacker
controled device to authenticate into
the victim's account and and you could
use that to get account takeover via the
password reset flow and it was like I
can't believe that this actually worked
so you you'd think that I would I would
learn my lesson after you know to like
keep actually look at authentication
more often but you know sometimes it
just doesn't S K that's awesome that's
awesome and you didn't even say the word
rate limiting I'm so proud of you oh
yeah that's true rate limiting yeah I
said dumb multiactor bypasses like just
navigating to the thing anyway I was
waiting for you to say rate limied cuz
that's like the that's like the goto MFA
High Pass which is that you can Brute
Force OTP codes it's screwed so many
companies too if you can figure out a
way to to you know yeah definitely
Facebook pays a lot of money for that
yeah yeah they've paid
multiple mid to high five figure crits I
believe for that that bug that
specifically yep
ridiculous all right next up we've got a
clip from episode 47 uh in which we
talked about CSP research if frame
hopping and clientside shenanigan
this clip is particularly talking about
the open-faced iframe sandwich a
technique which will allow you to
exploit uh excesses in subdomains that
aren't necessarily attached to the main
domain hope you enjoy this one one thing
that I wanted to share that we mentioned
on the on the Discord and I realized
wasn't really sort of common knowledge
for people is this sort of concept of an
iframe sandwich uh and it's not really
an iframe sandwich but it's sort of like
an open iframe sandwich okay and and so
uh this is something that you can do
because I've mentioned before on the Pod
and in other mediums that if you have a
Target that iframes in a subdomain okay
so let's say one of one of the the first
time I actually fully exploited this the
scenario was uh my target domain I
framed in a marketing subdomain where
you could control your email preferences
or whatever right okay not a huge impact
in that scenario but I did something
cool with it with ooth stuff and got ATL
um
no big deal the yeah but um uh in that
scenario the iframe domain which is
different from the a different domain
from the primary domain if you can pop
an xss on that iframed domain you can do
some cool [__] okay so what you can do
is from an attacker and keep in mind
this domain is is iframed so normally it
has um you know iframe allow
configurations so what you can do from
your attacker control page you can
iframe in and do an visible frame to
that subdomain where you have the xss
pop the xss get JS control okay then
from the attacker controlled page pop
open a new tab to the the victim domain
that you would like to attack and that
victim domain has the xss vulnerable
subdomain iframed in right and then what
you can do is you can reach from the
iframe on the attacker controlled page
up to the attacker page over to the the
victim domain and then down into the xss
domain um on that page by using
different frames and because you control
um js on the iframe on your page you can
modify the content of the iframe on the
victim domains page right that's if
framed into the victim domains page and
you can affect that content so let's say
in that scenario you can rewrite that
content with like you know uh something
that might could leak tokens something
that could you know you could put even a
uh you know sort of a fishing thing in
there and that sort of thing is is
normally accepted in my experience
because you're affecting the Integrity
of the inscope application by modifying
the contents of a domain that they are
iframing into their website um and and
so I kind of call this an iframe
sandwich it's not really you know when
iframes used to be a little bit more
permissive you could do some cooler
stuff with that but um just making sure
you understand how frames work and and
what kind of stuff you can access using
parent using opener using understand
this yeah yeah on let's say victim.com
you have one t open victim.com right
inside it they have vulnerable. comom
yes yeah vulnerable. comom or you know
vulnerable. victim.com or
something
vi. so now get exercise you have an
exercise inside an i frame on uh on Vic
well
not exactly okay so let me let me break
it down a little bit a little bit better
you've got your you've got two frames or
two pages two tabs with if frames in
them okay okay one is an attacker
control or an attacker page and one of
them is the victim page both of them
have an if frame
to um access has vulnerable domain right
okay using the ex you can't control the
the path in that is iframed into the
victim's domain so that's always going
to be iframed to wherever the victim
says it's it should go right okay but on
the attacker controlled page you you can
control it so you pop xss through that
reach back up through the attacker
controlled page reach over to the the
tab that's opened up uh the other
iframed page reach into the I frame and
modify the content does that make sense
okay yeah so it's it's almost backwards
instead like you're modifying the the
victim page from the attacker page
exactly because it's the same iframe in
both them because it's the same origin
yeah right same origin so you can
communicate with ey frames of the same
origin in a different tab is there a
better way to explain this because I I
had the same trouble you explain from
the other way around it was a little
confusing because it was kind of like
you get an xss within this ey frame and
then you set up your own P like I I
think the way you just described it now
is better where basically you have two
pages they both I from the same URL you
have an xss in both of them but you can
easily pop it from your attacker page
which then you can use that context to
communicate with the context they both
in the other page you iframe they both
the same domain but probably a different
URL if it's a reflected xss yeah you
know like there's no saying that like
maybe on victim.com right like that
you'd be able to actually pop it through
the URL or something maybe it's an
attack a complex attack scenario it
doesn't really matter because all you
need is control over that iframe context
with the same origin right yeah exactly
exactly and as long as you control
you're running JS execution right on
that on that origin and you have a path
to reach the the other frame right in
this scenario it would
be parent oh that's why
you if
frame is that why you open it from
victim.com why you have to open it from
victim.com
no no no well you you have you have
attacker controlled page with the with
the xss in would you just open the
victim page from your attacker page
exactly that one yeah and then you hop
over there and modify it um man maybe I
should uh maybe let me let me make a
note here what
we need a cardboard box diagram from
I'll I'll uh I'll draw a little draw a
diagram for iframe sandwich um I'll draw
a little diagram and put it on the
screen for those of you watching so
basically you you open attacker.com
attacker.com opens a new tab with
victim.com they both if frame the same
URL you pop the xss from your
attacker.com in in the iframe which can
then communicate with the iframe in the
other tab on victim.com and then you can
either control the content you can do
whatever you want within that if frame
exactly yeah and and and you know um
depending on the refer policy and stuff
like that you might be able to to leak
uh you know you uh ooth parameters and
that sort of thing um so all sorts of
cool stuff you can do with that it's a
good way to take an xss in a subdomain
that's you know maybe not even in scope
or less important and make it affect the
primary domain and increase your
impact next up also from episode 47
there's a Super Hot Topic in the
industry right now called JS hoisting
and we decided to discuss that I of
course got nerd sniped and was getting
distracted trying to figure out how this
all works so you're not going to want to
miss this one so I'm I'm going down a
path of trying to represent things from
an audio perspective it's going to be
tricky but okay let's say we had a fun
an injection at a place in the JS where
it was x.y where neither X nor y were
defined okay can you control them no you
can't control them they're not defined
and then it's it's it's a function call
so it's calling the function x.y the
first parameter is one there's a comma
and then you injecting okay and you can
inject anything you want except for
script tag you have to stay inside the
script right um how do you get this to
resolve because as soon as it reads the
line it's going to say x is undefined uh
you know or Y is undefined can't access
read a property on undefined error and
then your code is never going to run um
and so I was looking at this I was like
I know that there's a way to exploit
this I can't figure out what it was and
I tried actually the solution that ended
up working but I was missing one stupid
little piece um and the answer to this
problem is something called JS hoisting
have you heard of JS hoisting Joel I
don't know if I've heard of the term but
if you explain it to me I might I might
have heard of it yeah so the term is JS
hoisting and it's essentially the
concept that functions in JS defined
using and some other um objects as well
but mostly for this case functions
defined using the function
keyword despite where they are in the
flow will be hoisted to the top of the
of the script execution flow so if you
define a function at the very bottom
using the function keyword of a script
tag and you call that function above
where that function is defined it'll
work because the function definition is
getting moved up to the top of um the
the script okay so in this scenario what
we were able to do was Define the
function X okay and uh and what that
would do is it would Hoist the
definition up to the top so now the
variable X now contains a valid function
okay so when you try to access the
property y on X you don't get an error
but you get Y is undefined then it will
attempt to call the the undefined uh y
because of the function call and when it
does that it will parse the parameters
that are being passed into that function
and at that point when it pars the
parameters you can do a function call in
the parameters themselves um and that
will get executed before it attempts to
call Y which will inevitably fail
because you can't call undefined um and
in that way we were able to get
arbitrary script execution and pop it
into an xss because of this concept
called JS wasting so I wanted to shout
that out there because we're big fans of
of uh that kind of crazy Edge Fringe
JavaScript [__] here on the Pod um and
I'm not I wasn't even sure yeah I I I I
feel like most people haven't heard of
it so I I would have been surprised if
you had heard of that Joel yeah I was I
was just testing some things around he's
got a he's got a handheld mic and he's
trying to type and speak into the yeah I
was testing some things around this uh
to see if there's a better way and I
think there might be without having to
break out
of the whole
thing all right this is like classic
Joel nerd sniped [__] right here okay
all right Joel reain it in reain it in
bring it back to the Pod okay what I was
gonna say is okay he's still freaking
looking at it I am still freaking
looking at it I was just gonna X not F
okay um yeah so the JS hoisting thing it
seems that so context is important right
um basically my thought was like maybe
you could do this without having to
break out of the function um but even if
you define X within the parameters it
doesn't work because it's within the
like so you can do it never gets
evaluated because it fails right in the
beginning right so like you you uh
tweeted out uh a similar like an xss
challenge like a while ago and it had to
do with essentially in JavaScript
there's a behavior where you can use
commas to provide multiple statements
and and you can assign variables to the
last variable the last thing that is
returned in that comma sequence um and
you canuse that in a similar way here um
where you can use that that for like you
know one comma what and you can just
within your parameters you can do the
same thing um but because it's within
that context of it's already trying to
call it it seems that it has to be like
what you said like you have to Define it
because it's going to try and call it
before it evaluates um well it it's
gonna try to read the the yeah like the
object itself so it's GNA say does the
object exist then it gets the parameters
then it passes them into the function
call exactly and when it tries to say
hey I need to get the x or the Y
property of X then and X is undefined
then you can't get a property of
undefined and then that'll error right
um so shout out to bit k um and to Johan
and a couple of the other people that I
think Carl also Carell origin um also
got it um and was able to to exploit
this so uh definitely I appreciate the
the help there and I learned a lot about
JavaScript that day because then I had
to deep of course I had to Deep dive JS
hoist so there's a bunch of um you can
do it with variables you can do it with
classes but the cool thing about
functions is it's not just
um the thing doesn't just get defined it
gets sort of it's initialized to it's an
actual object I'm pretty sure the
reasoning for this was that like way
back in the day there was a there was a
historical problem with programming
languages where if you define something
after it was used it couldn't be called
and I think this is the most common with
like C and C++ and stuff but if you had
a function was like if your main
function essentially wasn't at the end
of your program then you couldn't like
call anything else because it didn't
know it existed I think this was maybe
why header files ex I don't know I'm I'm
not an expert on this but essentially
like that's part of what JS is trying to
solve here is that like if you call
something before it's defined it should
still be able to call it even if because
it's defined it's just that like it it
does some restructuring and like I don't
know yeah yeah it's super interesting um
well reing that existing Behavior to to
work in in your in your favor yeah the
the other interesting thing with this is
that um it doesn't it doesn't work for
variables to find a functions so for
example if you did VAR x equals function
blah blah blah blah and defined it that
way like you're defining a variable
pointing to a function rather than using
the function keyword then it won't work
but if you use the function keyword um
as the primary expression in that that
line of code then um it will it will
hoist it so lots of cool lots of cool
things I was just talking to my my
brother-in-law the other day who's a
programmer and we were talking he was
saying he freaking hates JavaScript and
I was like man I love JavaScript because
JavaScript there's so many ways to get
everything done and there's so many
quirks to the language it's like a
hacker's dream it really
is it really is yeah it's super
interesting that um if you define it as
a variable it works but doesn't
work what do you mean so when you when
you do like if you do varx equals
function afterwards after the call it'll
say cannot read properties of oh no it
doesn't work sorry I misread I misre it
my bad sorry well sometimes it'll so
there is something you can do with VAR
because VAR will Hoist the the
definition to the top or the um
initialization no not that the
definition to the top but not the
initialization there we go um or maybe
it's the Declaration that's what I'm
looking for it it'll Hoist the
Declaration but it will not Hoist the
initialization um and so that's a little
bit of a of a quirky thing
there and with that we're on to the
interview section we've got a lot of
great guests on this list and first up
is Shan yo from asset node we had a
great conversation with him surrounding
everything Recon and specifically the
clip we took for today is diving into
what should be your primary key in your
recon infrastructure should it be IPS
should it be subdomains I think Sean has
a really nuanced answer so I hope you
enjoy it what for example one of things
that I I I and we were talking about
earlier today with OTA was um you know
dividing out your domains and your IP
addresses logically and and not making
your your subdomain your primary key
right like that was my when I that was
my biggest architectural mistake I made
when I built my Recon system was I was
like I was obsessed with subdomains yeah
I was like subdomain is is the end all
be all but really at the end of the day
it all goes down to I you know IP
addresses I shouldn't say that but it
mostly all goes down well I mean that's
a good point CU I think so this is the
kind of discussion I want to have is
like you know what what are those those
mistakes like focusing on subdomains
instead of focusing IP addresses as the
lowest level of logical entities and you
know mapping those because yeah I think
it also comes to like what kind of Recon
are you doing right and I think
subdomains is fine because a lot of
things like subdomains is the easiest
identifiable way of looking at something
yeah the reason you say IP addresses is
relevant is because there's a whole
bunch of assets and like what we yeah
what we consider assets that might not
have a subdomain Associated right like
companies
like or just sub that you don't know
yeah they don't like they exist on the
internet you just can't see them yet but
there's also like a whole separate set
of pitfalls like when you start to go to
that level because IPS rotate like
things subdomains get reassigned so like
you might have an IP address that's
stored and then you scan you're like oh
my God there's a new service on this
it's exploitable and it turns out it
belongs to somebody else like it's it's
not even theirs and then you report it
to the company and they're like we don't
we don't own this IP yeah yeah that's
true I mean yeah I think it all it all
depends on and this is kind of what we
were talking about earlier sort of
correlation factors and I think that
could definitely be a new logical entity
in a Recon structure system you know
like like you have this this domain and
you've got that you know database what
you know about that domain and you've
got this a subdomain meaning and or fqdn
and then you got this IP address and
then you've got some sort of
relationship between the two
that's corelated could be DNS entry
correlates them it could be a TLS Sni
you know it could be you know um
historical data it could be you know
what what else could it be I'm trying to
what do you think Bing over this idea
for a couple years and I tried to
implement this at ASE but the use case
is very nuanced right so when you start
getting into more and more Cloud native
apps the ways you identify what you
consider like an asset starts to change
very differently yeah right in a very
traditional old school setting it would
probably be like we have IP addresses on
servers and that's it we might give them
a sub doain but when you get to like the
other end of the spectrum Uber starts
routing Things based on your subpar um
and if you want to be more specific Uber
starts routing Things based on your sub
paath in a specific geolocation yeah
right so even if you hit the same IP
address with the same subdomain same Sni
same path you'll be hitting two
different data centers that might be
running different versions of your app
right even further it might be getting
featur flagged and routed to another
version of the app based on your user ID
right and all of these means that at the
end of the day the app you're looking at
might not even be the same one um you
might be getting like a China version of
The Uber app versus a America version of
The Uber app sure or even you might be
getting a beta Uber app versus the
production app right and I think
factoring all of these in into like what
you call this correlation U probably is
overkill for most people um yeah but I
want it to be perfect but you want to be
perfect well how about this for every
single you create a unique correlation
right
so you build your mental model you grab
cosmin back and you ask him how does
deploy their apps right and then you
work backwards from there you say I
factor it doesn't care about geolocation
they don't care about user ID they care
about the tenant ID they care about
their subdomain whatever but for Uber
totally different story now we're an
entire different Paradigm he's a new
correlation method right you want to go
to the nth degree you might as well it's
it's in and and no I mean you made a
perfect point which is that we can't
over I mean you so perfectly pointed out
that that flaw of like this is just
going to be way over engineering some of
these some of these things and and at
the end of the day you are going to you
are going to you know run into these
these scenarios where you're like ah
it's not perfect but then you gota you
got to decide is the trade-off of that
fixing that problem actually going to
get me enough bounties to justify the
time that I'm spending on and to that a
lot of the time is no I mean sometimes
unless you want to make it your thing
yeah like sometimes it's worth hacking
around it right you might have the
system that works for 90% of the cases
and then you decide okay I'm going to
spend like 3 weeks looking at Google
infrastructure right and now this is
this entire ownb that has its own books
written on it um so I'm just going to
hack together something that's just for
this and maybe you find that I've now
spent three months on it I understand it
enough now I can merge it back into
Mainline and feed this across the rest
of it but you don't have to make
everything into your giant monolithic
Beast right you can always have smaller
pieces that's for something else and
then once you sort of figure out how
this works it then comes back naturally
into the rest of the work you're doing
in this clip from episode 30 we're
talking with chubs all about reverse
engineering enterprise software to find
awesome zero days you know it seems like
you guys have really found some amazing
bones together and one of the common
threads that I noted across all this
because I'm I'm not proficient in this
specific area is the use of a dynamic
analysis um you know of hooking up a
debugger to it and you know stepping
through the code and breaking at certain
points and stuff like that um so you
know it can you talk to me a little bit
more about that process and how that's
changed your approach to Enterprise
software yeah for sure uh I mean
debugging is almost necessary when when
we're looking at complex enterprise
software sometimes unfortunately it's
just not possible and and we we we don't
have the installation file or we can't
install it like some of the Oracle
software that's out there and it's just
too tricky to to get up and running but
right but nine times out of 10 we're
looking to get a debuger going because
um most of the vulnerabilities that we
find they can be really complex and
without a debugger we can't figure out
exactly you know what are the variables
at a certain break point how do we
manipulate them to get what we want um
and and things like that so these days
um most of the projects that we debug
from a I guess just from a a dynamic
analysis perspective is mostly Java and
net projects for for Java we use
intellig um which is you know you can
get the Community Edition it works fine
out of the box and you can start
debugging things for net we use Ryder
and that's also from jet brains and
that's beautiful like honestly Ryder you
can attached directly to a process it
starts decompiling everything for you
and you can start sending break points
quite easily so for for those two
languages that's what we use um and I
think um when it comes to Binary
analysis we obviously we use things like
like GDB and things like that to do do
our Dynamic analysis um but yeah Dylan
um he's honestly um one of the the best
researchers that I've ever worked with
um
H he's great he's he's so great that
like sometimes sometimes he's very quiet
so sometimes he'll be quiet for six
hours or something and I'll ask him like
What's the progress and he like yeah I
got an or Bypass or a shell or I see I'm
like dude you could have told me earlier
I've been like on the edge of my seat
this whole time you know what I mean so
so um so Dylan sometimes quiet but he's
he's very very good I mean his
background you know if you're not
hearing him they're getting into
something you know
like yeah yeah and he's he's he's he's
just so
multidisciplinary um he has um such good
skills in Java and net um but he's able
to get his hands quite dirty with uh
binary exploitation and Analysis as well
which is something that's incredibly
valuable for us as you guys have seen
like recently the Citrix vulnerabilities
have come out and where it was like a
race to patch diff them and find the the
rce so so without Dylan we wouldn't have
been able to do that work basically yeah
no he he seems like a really valuable
addition to the team and and yeah I'm
always watching that that vog very uh
you know hopeful for the next one to
come out do you have any any teasers for
us any anything you want to tell us
about coming up
soon yeah yeah for sure there was a
metabase pre-or rce that was announced
um around a week ago so that that's
that's the next thing coming up it's
done by myself and an ex- colleague of
mine um and we're we'll be releasing
that on August 20 uh that's saw you
mentioning that in in bug Bounty forum
for sure but the hey has anybody
somebody posted they like hey does
anybody know anything about this
metabase RC and shs just replies yeah
asset don't found that yeah it was it
was it was a really fun bug and I think
people are going to really enjoy the
chain cuz it was not straightforward and
our final exploit payload has like maybe
five or six different tricks in one
payload so it's really really fun to fun
to see um but but um you know we'll see
there's already Chinese um researchers
that have reproduced the issue and
they've posted tweets of a blurred burp
window of the issue so if it drops
before August 20 we'll drop our block
post gotcha wow dude that's awesome I I
I love to get the little sneak peek here
so thanks for sharing that that's that's
great um so I guess asset note so going
going going to asset note right um just
for those of you that that aren't
familiar asset note is the um I guess
Enterprise security software that um uh
I guess how I'll let you describe it
chubs it's a it's a Recon it started off
as a reconnaissance software uh in order
to help you do asset management but it's
evolved to so much
more that's right so originally it was
an open source project that was just to
discover assets as quickly as possible
but now basically what ason note does is
it discovers all the assets that belong
to your organization on the external
attack surface and it continuously
monitors it for exposures so it finds
security vulnerabilities and indicators
that that that organizations can use but
you know like the the difference between
a Indie homegrown open source bug Bounty
tool and an Enterprise product that we
sell to the largest Enterprises in the
world there's just so much in between so
so different it's just so different and
and I you know I mean I see a lot of the
the Frameworks out there that get
released and and all that sort of stuff
and um they're excellent but I just
think that like to to sell to
Enterprises there's just so many demands
that aren't even things that are on
people's minds when it comes to building
software um necessarily that that has
been very interesting to to work yeah
yeah for sure so this product you know
has evolved from Recon to to Asset
Management to Asset Management plus
vulnerabilities and then you know also
it seems like this research branch has
sort of come out of it now is is that is
that a supplement to the product is that
kind of how you're seeing it or why did
you guys decide to start this research
side of the of the
company yeah we we just identified like
we because we have access to all of this
reconnaissance data for all of our
customers including the Technologies
right we identified that we have this
really unique opportunity to do security
research in a way that's targeted
towards our customers and basically our
security research team has maybe like
two or three functions I'd say the the
main function is satisfying the needs of
our customers when it comes to when a
new vulnerability comes out like the
Citrix rce like we've we've got plenty
of customers that hit us up being like
do you have a check for this and that
like for for a very long time I was the
single person on the security research
team doing this sort of work but after a
certain point there's just so many
different new vulnerabilities that are
getting released that we need to stay on
top of we needed a research team it was
a natural progression inside the product
like we can't offer a great like
exposure scanning service if we aren't
staying on top of the new patches being
released new vulnerabilities being
released even new nuclei releases for
example we need to stay on top of
because there might be something in
there that you know might affect our
customers but um the research Branch
also has a second um purpose which is
marketing and you might have noticed
that you know like at asset node we
don't actually invest that much money
into traditional marketing like we don't
have like crazy campaigns for
traditional marketing we don't have
Banners at Black
get private
rooms of that
Stu and I mean guys like there might be
a time in the future where we have to do
that sort of stuff as the as the company
progresses but but until now which is a
fiveyear journey till now we've relied
on our technical um content to be the
biggest marketing that we do and um I
can say it's been incredibly successful
um I think from our technical marketing
we get probably the most inbound leads I
think if we could attribute them all um
which is just you know as a business
it's not a bad model yeah no that's
that's amazing go ahead Joel yeah so
which one would you say sort of drives
the other one would you say that your
research team is more like finding new
things reversing patches providing those
vulnerabilities like as soon as possible
to your customers or your customers
prompting you with hey we heard about
this vulnerability or we're affected by
this vulnerability can you guys check
for it and then you the research team
goes and looks into it so so we we we
split up our research stream into two
different things which is reactive and
proactive and um the reactive stream um
is is obviously like when customers
reach out or anything gets released on
the internet things like that we
prioritize reactive over proactive but
we do definitely still have a lot of
time left for proactive research so um I
mean it's it's um for us the number one
priority is our customers and what they
what their requests are so we often even
work with customers to get access to
software that we may not typically have
access to but um that's that's where we
spend most of our time is for customer
concerns dude it that's that's just what
what an amazing service what an amazing
product you guys have developed there
and I I love that it it it Roots its
Origins are in security research in a in
a thorough understanding from a
technical level of what kind of stuff
gets you pwned you know and and and
going after that like these cve
reversing um you know sprees that you
guys have gone on and I and I loved that
piece as well about you breaking it up
into reactive and proactive I think
that's really really um awesome and I
imagine on the proactive side you know
what what you're doing for that is is
you're looking you know you're looking
at all of your your customers you
alluded to this before but you're
looking at all of your customers
technology stacks and I mean do you just
pick the one with the you know greatest
number or are you looking for specific
things like okay this is Java or this is
net so I know I can hook up a debugger
to it and have a better chance of
finding a
v we we'll be ready to Target anything
that has enough exposure for our
customers but like for example we looked
at C panel um and that's written was
crazy and that's like crazy and written
in Pearl and like all these C binaries
and stuff is honestly a mess like as a
security researcher you go into that
project and you're like I really don't
like working with this project but but
ultimately we'll we'll do anything but
but um the proactive side just to note
on that um while we look at our
customers Technologies we're also not
afraid to look at technologies that our
customers may not be running now but we
might see it on a perspective customer
or we might see it on the attack surface
in the future um and this this is often
just popular software so if there's any
really popular enterprise software
that's usually a good enough Target for
us that's that's awesome man so so I
guess that's that's for you guys you
guys have a great and we can sort of
apply these principles to bug Bounty as
well you know we can look at the
programs we're in we can fingerprint the
Technologies and we can do the same
thing um but but specifically from the
cve you know reversing perspective can
you speak to how that could help a bug
Bounty Hunter and what kind of skills
they would develop as well as you know
what kind of results they might see if
they invest more time into um zero day
research or more specifically cve
reversing and and just to tag on to that
a little bit can you also maybe talk
about the amount of time it takes and
sort of what the input versus output
looks like on these types of
things yeah I would say that um most cve
reversing work doesn't usually lead to
immense amount of bounties if there's a
lot of patching going on but sure for
example if you were to take if you were
to take the metabase research for
example um then I think you could
potentially get a few bounties out of
that um I when it comes to inputs and
outputs I mean it really just depends on
every project every project can be you
know like for example for Citrix there
was no information that they provided in
their advisory that would even hint to
us where this may be located it wasn't
until we had other people in the
industry publish more things like Bishop
Fox that we saw okay there's some more
information here we can work with this
and find potentially what what they're
referring to and and there's always the
problem of Silent patches which is uh
probably the most frustrating part of
this whole CV reversing game um where
they'll release an advisory for an RC
that's critical but they'll patch like
five other things in that same release
that they don't talk about so I mean
there's a lot of there's a lot of
variability when it comes to whether or
not we'll find what we're looking for in
the CV reversing project certainly it's
much easier on Java based and net
projects when it comes to Binary based
projects that's where it gets really
difficult because you're suddenly now
you're you're diffing the bins and
there's like just so much you know so
much to go through that's very esoteric
and very difficult to understand at a
glance so it's easy to miss things in
binary projects but there's this
intersection right with with with web
and binary when it comes to appliances
like you know vpns and firewalls and
things like that and we we have to spend
more time on this sort of work because
um ultimately these products are Exposed
on the internet and can lead to a show
on their Network so by Nature Yeah
Yeah Yeah from a bug Bounty perspective
I think the most profitable thing to do
is find zero days and report them to
programs but there is a lot of
controversy around that as you guys all
know let's uh let's start that
conversation yeah yeah yeah um I I mean
I I personally I personally think
there's a lot of value almost like what
assd note does right uh but from the bug
Bounty perspective of getting your hands
on a a vulnerability with advanced
notice right because um you know the
patch Cycles especially for some of
these bigger companies um they're going
to be a little bit longer and and um
it's hard to track down all your assets
as as you know as the asset list grows
and grows and grows
um and so you know by Nature if you get
a couple you know months head start on
on oh this this B is going to be
released and you know just ah Heads Up
You're vulnerable uh I think that adds a
lot of value and I think that's
something that company should pay for
whether it should be you know their full
Max crit or whether it should be you
know some bonus or some lower amount um
that's you know to be determined I guess
by the by the company but uh that's my
position on it do you guys what do you
guys think
need to hear what Joel thinks I mean
yeah yeah let's hear Joel okay so from a
from a company perspective yeah um it's
a it's it's definitely a tricky
situation right like I I I see both
sides a lot better than I think some
other people in the industry do mainly
because I'm both a bug Bounty Hunter and
like a absec engineer so from like the
company perspective it's very tricky
when you're using a vendor product and
you get that reported as a vulnerability
because the reality is that all you can
do is wait for the vendor to fix it
especially if it's a zero day so there's
no actual I mean you can like turn it
off or you know there are like certain
preventative measures you can do but you
can't actually fix it until the company
fixes it and all that you would be kind
of expected to do is tell the company
hey we got this zero day do you know
about this and if the company says no we
don't know about that then it's like
you're in a weird spot where you've kind
of ruined the research
spoils and also alerted the company and
now the company's like hey why don't we
know about this um and it but like if
you don't report it then like you're
kind of like missing your ethical
boundaries so I it's very very tricky
from a researcher perspective I think
you should just report it to the company
and then go ham like that kind of sets
your ethical liability a little bit
lower because you've told the company
now it's up to the company to fix it if
they fix it really fast and they tell
their customers and the customers
updated really fast then good job but
you've you know notified and now it's
kind of fair game for you at least I
think and then whatever happens happens
right if if companies start telling the
the vendor that their product is
vulnerable and they've been receiving
this zero day then the that's kind of on
the vendor now because the vendor hasn't
fixed it fast enough or now the customer
is hearing about it so I I think it all
kind of goes back on the vendor but as a
researcher the main thing that I would
want to do is make sure that I've at
least told company and then spray and
pre you know yeah for sure I I I want to
hear I've got so many things I want to
say about that Joel but I want to hear
shubz I want to hear shub's opinion
first yeah Joel I agree with you you
report it to the company first and then
you report it to the bug Bounty programs
but man like in the last few weeks I've
even had a situation where you know it's
been really gut-wrenching because I had
this preor reported it to the vendor
then reported it to a handful of bug
Bounty programs
and um the mistake that you know that
that that was made was I didn't tell
this vendor that I'd reported it to
these bug Bounty programs specifically
and as a result they they wrote this
like email to me where it was like you
know gut-wrenching and they were like
you know asset note became the best
people we knew to just those guys and I
was like ah [__] like I didn't really
mean for that relationship with the
vendor but but this is the game like
this is this is the zero day Zero Day
game and at the end of the day what what
what I find surprising is I I mean their
perspective on this they're welcome to
have their perspective but the
vulnerability in question if I went to
an exploit broker I think I could have
sold it for 50 to $100,000 probably for
that that vulnerability now in this case
it's really really surprising because in
the bug bounties I must have made like
two or four grand it's like a very small
amount of money to be making from this
at the end of the day we reported the
zero day to the vendor for no cost and
this was zero day research that we did
that definitely cost us money so it was
our vulnerability that cost us money to
find and we report it to the vendor for
free and then we report it to bug Bounty
programs after we've reported it to the
vendor at that point I'm really
struggling to understand where like you
know where we've gone so wrong in this
equation when ultimately we've we've
just tried to report it to programs that
have this issue on their attack surface
I think there are a few nuances also
just quickly on on what Joel has
mentioned about this is where like you
should try your best not to report zures
and Cloud products like SAS products
onto other companies because there's
really no resolution at all that a
company can do like you talked about the
preventative measures that's possible
you can add a WAFF rule you can shut it
down you can segregated the network
things like that when it's like a an xss
on a that's a Zer
in there's like very little that a
customer can do to prevent that from
being exploited on their their attack
surface so yeah that's where it gets
trickier so so it's really funny that
hold on it's really funny that you say
that because I can think of one or two
instances actually more than that where
a researcher has reported something and
they say hey we've been doing a lot of
research and we have this zero day in
Cloud product here's a giant link that
just like pops an xss or something and
you're like okay now what like what do I
do oh man yeah so I mean like on one
hand I feel that and I and I understand
what you coming from as well you know
Joel with like okay there's not really a
lot the company can do but wouldn't you
still want to know like it like you know
that that that's where I kind of say
like when people put in their in their
policy that they don't want zero day
reports I'm like that's really silly you
know maybe to find something that's like
all right we'll pay a medium for or
maybe we'll you know decrease the
severity by one so if it's a crit you
know we'll drop it to a you know a
medium or you know but something like
that but even in even in cloud services
you know with with with the way that Sam
site cookies are working nowadays if you
if you are able to compromise a domain
uh you know subdomain within a company's
you know domain then you are able to do
so many more different attacks than you
would be able to do before you know it's
a really it's a it's a real problem um
and so that's kind of why I'm an
advocate for doing something like yes
we'll take the Zer day reports but we're
going to maybe lower the Bounty maybe
not lower the Bounty depending on the
impact and if we do have to pull it
offline if it's an rce on a VPN
Appliance right you better pull that
[__] offline and just tell your
employees to to get you know a different
way into the company for that time being
because you know if you get popped there
that's very very high value and we all
know anybody who's ever conducted an
external pen test knows you know as soon
as you get in and you get to the or
external to internal pen test as soon as
you get in that's it you know like
there's it's almost never segmented in
such a way that you cannot just get
literal keys to the kingdom once you get
in inside so I don't know that's my
thought on it in this next clip from
episode 30 we're talking with shubz
about advice he has for people building
out their Recon flow enjoy for the
hunter that is building a a
reconnaissance setup now um you know you
having gone through all of the you know
many many problems of of you know that
you faced building asset note what what
kind of advice do you have to to the bug
bounty hunter that wants to build a
continuous reconnaissance
platform yeah for their own use in just
to be clear yeah well I think like
Justin I remember you came to me um a
couple years ago and you said to me hey
man I'm seeing all these people move to
goang like do I need to move to goang as
well does this is this the right option
to make
remember yeah and it was just like
because I remember at that point I was
maybe 2 three years into the asset note
um adventure and we had migrated
everything to goang from the very
beginning so so I had experience working
in your stack that you're familiar with
which is just like basic python you know
everything's pretty straightforward you
can understand it without too much
complexity whereas our goang stack for
our Enterprise customers which can get
quite complex with the number of
microservices and things going on I
remember saying to you like choose
whatever you're most comfortable with
and what you can iterate in quickly on
it doesn't matter if it's goang or
python or whatever it could be Visual
Basic like Eric does right it doesn't
really matter what language it is but
but I remember you were like really
happy with that because you thought that
you had to move to a different language
you thought that you were put into this
position where the industry is moving
and the industry is changing languages
to everything in goang for various
reasons so I have to do it too and to be
frank I was the one in that position
when I started aseno and I decided to
move to goang there were many benefits
that we got out of that but I'm sure if
we worked hard enough we could get
something working in python as well um
it's it's not really the the distinction
of how good the product is going to be
and I see I see this trap a lot with you
know people will rewrite things in a new
language like they'll say oh there's XYZ
tool in this language I'm going to write
it in Rust now because rust is so hot
right now and everything's amazing in
Rust but the outcomes are usually the
same like usually the outcomes are very
similar or the same sometimes there's
speed differences acceptable I
understand but at the end of the day are
you going to learn a whole new language
to get that bit of speed difference or
are you going to build your systems in a
language you're comfortable with that
you can iterate quickly on so that's
definitely one of the advices that I
would give um the other one would be
like really think about your data
sources um as much as I would like to
say that you know our reconnaissance
techniques and and all of that are a
huge contributor there's also a huge
element where the data that we have
access to is just overpowered compared
to other uh other people's data sources
so that that sort of stuff if you start
looking at things like passive DNS if
you start investigating these things and
start understanding where you can get
these data sources what these data
sources look like how much you're
willing to pay for them you're suddenly
putting yourself at an immense Advantage
compared to almost every other bug
Bounty Hunter out there and um I think
one last thing is um just have an
environment where you can quickly
iterate code on when I was first
building asset Noe I did all of my
programming in the equivalent of GitHub
code build so back then there was
something called Cloud9 and I I used
that to do all of my iteration it was so
quick like I was building so so quickly
today you've got things like code spaces
I think sorry in in in GitHub that's an
equivalent of what I was using back then
um when I was building the very first
iterations of asset n wow dude that was
just a a treasure Trove of of advice
there thank you so much for sharing that
and I I remember that conversation very
clearly and I ju I left that
conversation like you said ecstatic you
know with the result of what you said
and it served me well for the rest of
the time you know that I was in the
Recon game like being able to quickly
develop code in Python it it was it was
invaluable and I think also one of the
great things that that just came out of
that conversation for me was
appreciation for that right because like
if I had gone down the other route and I
and I had you know written all this Goan
code I might oh man I I used to remember
when I used to be able to write code you
know off the top of my head without even
thinking about it in Python that's
that's great but you know and then I
would have earned the ability to like
you know um you appreciate python but
without having to go that through that
difficulty and that route you made me
aware every time I wrote python code
quickly how much of a blessing that is
and how much of a you know the win that
was so thank you so much for your advice
man that that really that really made a
big difference in my Recon game in this
last clip from episode 30 shubz drops
some hot hot spicy hacker advice on how
to hack IIs servers he's the master on
this you're not going to want to skip
this one so I I did have a couple more
things that I wanted to ask um
specifically specifically regarding IIs
um which is your bread and butter it
seems right you've done a lot of you've
done some videos on I stuff which will
link in the description and um what can
you tell us about hacking IAS servers
what what do you have for the
people yeah for sure I think I think the
second you see an is server you should
thank God because it's the easiest thing
to hack out of all the other web servers
that are out there you should be
grateful you should be grateful that you
you've come across the presence of an i
server you see that blue page that comes
up when you hit an i server that that
should be your your point in time where
you think I'm going to find criticals on
this oh my gosh love that because 90% of
the time like like like guys if you
think about every other web server
technology which other web server
technology lets you guess partial files
and folder names there's nothing out
there like that like that that's just
ridiculous and this vulnerability this
issue has existed for like 10 years plus
like it's been around for so long and it
still works on the latest version of I
like this is not even something that
they're thinking about seriously fixing
in future versions so far that I've seen
so there's that right you've got the
ability to see partial file names and
folders with enough reconnaissance you
can figure out the rest of those file
names and folders by doing some fuzzing
so on so forth then there's all this
other stuff that happens with net and
specifically with I and net where you
are able to get a shell if you get local
file disclosure now if you if you if you
get local file disclosure and read a
web.config file it has the machine key
the validation key you're able to
escalate that from just that to to
command execution again the the only
solution for this is you start storing
these values in the in the in the
Windows registry instead of the
web.config file 90% of the time
companies are storing it in the
web.config file and this is something
that you know often leads to command
execution once you get local far
disclosure then there's the other aspect
of this where when you when you
audit.net um products you've got to deal
with this whole idea of Windows shares
and windows domains so let's say you
find an ssrf that ssrf on an is server
on a net product is much more than just
reaching a web server nine times out of
10 if they're using path. jooin then in
path. jooin you can just do back
slashback slash uh and and put in like a
Windows share back/ C dollar sign back
slash and suddenly because of the
windows apis that are being used for
these Network requests Windows willingly
shares the ntlm net ntlm hash with your
server so you run responder on your
server and suddenly you've escalated an
ssrf to a critical much more critical
than just being HTTP requests so there's
stuff like that then there's like you
know I guess there's also this this also
this amazing thing with net and IAS
where there's like a thousand different
ways to drop a shell like when you drop
shells in I and net you can drop shells
with web. configs with ascx files with
ashx files with aspx files you can drop
shells in so many different ways it's
it's beautiful and it's really great to
be able to to to hack on on on on on net
is servers and one last thing that I
love one last thing is if you're
exploiting an xxe in in a in a net
application there is an xxc payload that
is universal for Windows that us uses a
a DTD file that's within the Windows
File system that's always present in the
Windows File system that will n times
out of 10 let you leak file contents
when you probably shouldn't be able to D
so these are all the different things
that's that's sick and I I want that
payload we're I'm going to make a note
right now get get the XS see payload
from shs uh because that that seems
really helpful I've seen some stuff
floing around but it'd be nice to have
it here you know and Link it down in the
description for the people that are
interested dude that that was such a
treasure Trove of of knowledge I I feel
like dude I'm so lucky to be able to
have you on here because I just like
throw a little like you know question
out there and then there's just like
boom gold boom gold boom gold and we
were actually just talking about the um
you know the the share paths last week
and how crazy it is that you get those
ntlm hashes um and and that you can
interact with shares you know when you
have ssrf as well um so that's that's
really cool really cool stuff um and
definitely for those of you that haven't
hacked on IAS stuff check out short uh
check out shorts scan um bit quirks uh
you know till day enumeration tool and
then also read all the writeups that
we'll link below uh for shs on IAS
related stuff because um like you said
man I get excited when I see that that
blue page and I think most other hackers
uh should as well um that's that's all I
had on the list for today um and chubs
do you have anything else you wanna you
want to share or anything you want to
talk about where can we find you on on
socials as
well uh just two last things I want to
share and then we can wrap it up great
one of them is when you see the blue
page on IAS do not skip it please yes
there's something there like there's
there's no reason they've just spun up
an is server for no reason like like
they wouldn't just do that most
companies have something there there is
something there please keep keep looking
keep finding it whatever there's
something there and the second thing is
um just one other lesser known technique
in IAS is virtual directory um virtual
like uh path traversal to Traverse into
different virtual servers via virtual
directories so in IAS you can set up
directories that are pointing to
different servers and if you use path
traversal within those directories you
can see the web rot of different servers
this is something that I found um quite
common in I deployments that are complex
so they'll have/ SSO pointing to
10.1.1.1 and but it's pointing to
10.1.1.1 SSO so you can gosso do do
percentage 2f and then that will route
you to 10.1.1.1 to the doc rout ah okay
so it's you're path traversing on the
backend server in the reverse Bo that's
right okay that's right yeah this is
similar to that's an IIs Behavior
specifically yes this is an IIs Behavior
specifically this is very similar to Sam
Curry's secondary context work right um
but but but then this this can lead to a
lot of crazy vulnerabilities because in
many cases they don't expect you to be
able to access the dock route of
10.1.1.1 and you can just brute force
and find whatever you want and and and
and go from there so that's the last tip
that I I don't think it's publicly
talked about that much so just want to
give that to your audience as
well all righty the next episode we have
up on the docket is episode 37 Tokyo
hacking an interview with Lupin this is
a great clip where we're talking about
JS Weil and cursor two awesome smart
JavaScript analysis plugins for vs code
and we also cover how to take that JS
data and build great word list for
things like car boyance or rest API
hacking
enjoy you mentioned a a when we were
walking down the street to the to the
freaking uh Shrine earlier today to meet
up with friends um you know you
mentioned that there was this VSS code
uh plugin that that you you've been
using um and I imagine it actually would
work well in conjunction with JS weasel
exactly and yeah could you talk a little
bit about that because that was a really
interesting product yeah so I saw uh the
Tweet of Corbin that basically used J
whizzle uh with cursor and cursor is
like a wrapper around vs code uh since
vs code is mostly open source and
basically they're embeding uh GPT 4
inside the vs code and you can directly
ask question about your code base what's
really interesting is that you can pay
um the subscription but you can also
directly natively use your gp4 IPI key
so you directly pay to open Ai and no
need to go through their servers okay
and um it's so amazing like uh right now
I I'm using it to do uh JavaScript
analysis on Google that they use like a
lot of RPC weird calls like it's
horrible proprietary protocol yeah and
basically I'm going like okay that's the
in point of uh the request right so what
are the parameters because they are like
so embedded in one function to another
function to another function and
basically I just asking the AI um tell
me which other function you want context
to so I can provide it to you and we can
reconstruct the request and I did that
like maybe five six times and at one
point I just got the request that I
needed to send and like the pro buff
request and I was like oh that's amazing
and it just built it automatically for
Wow and so I use J Wizzle to detect uh
which like like all endpoints you did
some automation also to get the IDS
right and then you just ask cursor okay
explain to me this code and this is the
job like instead of having like six to
seven hours of code review do it like
maybe in two hours it's so great I love
it wow it's really interesting like I
think this is something before AI or
like GPT was really yeah more you know
before it was as as flushed out as it is
this would be something that you might
have like code ql or maybe some more of
a technical tool be doing but this the
approach to basically just feeding it
into Ai and saying hey what do I need to
know about this it's so much more
powerful because it can do everything
just like in an instant where it just
analyzes this huge chunk of data and is
able to just parse it and tell you oh
yeah here's what you need to know I'm
I'm a little I'm a little confused about
how that works though because I feel
like the codebase would extend past the
context window any any do either of you
guys know how that works works or is it
with GPT for like 8K or something I
don't know um so uh basically when I use
it I select the lines of code I wanted
to interpret uh but they natively use a
way to uh compress the file and
basically they have like some kind of if
I understood correctly a search engine
on the client side that that depending
on the question will go look for the
code before and then giving the context
to open AI so you do not have to give
everything I see I see a bit like being
search is doing like the search engine
uh does the first request and then give
the data back to open Ai and openi will
uh put context I see I see yeah that's
really interesting because like what you
meant we were talking earlier about like
tokens and and sort of how like AI looks
at input as tokens and it splits it up
into different segments that it can
understand better and sort of looks at
those pieces individually and then we'll
build like the context together and I
think that's like what you said like it
it the way that it part is that is kind
of counter counterintuitive because you
might think like oh you know I can't
feed a giant folin but you can because
it it can do some more processing Magic
on it than than it would before um the I
mean like llm are trained on so many
data points that actually they can
complete context uh so if you say um
this function passes something they can
guess uh it's not like the the more
accurate way to do it but I I think the
cursor team did a great job about
knowing what to feed to the AI and
knowing like what they already know so
you you can like compress as much as
possible the tokens to not you know pay
the akk subscription right right right
um yeah and and I I think combining
those two tools together JS weasel and
and was it cursor cursor okay like mouse
cursor yeah okay gotcha gotcha um yeah
combining those two tools together is a
really powerful combo so shout out to
Corbin for for that one um uh yeah I'm
I'm definitely I'm definitely interested
to see where all that goes and JS weasel
uh I think we'll probably cover in a
little bit more detail on a different
episode um but I I booted it up for the
first time during this live hacking
event and I've been using it and uh it's
really cool to see it do automatically
what we talked about you know breaking
out those those um uh F web packed JS
files and having it you know drop all of
the things there um but I'm wondering I
don't know if you you've used it Joel
but for for you Lupin um I'm wondering
uh how you've been using the tool
because for me I I've been having a
little bit of a difficulty with and I
talked to Charlie about this and I think
he's fixing it but um I've been having a
little bit of difficulty with
identifying the portions of the JS code
that I really want to analyze because
there's not a search function presently
yeah um and so I mean do do you do you
have that same struggle have you worked
around it what how how are you using the
tool currently yeah um the the tool
misses like a search uh function
that's definitely something uh that that
needs to be implemented um the way I use
it is more about like um knowing the
attack surface and the constructing uh
World list out of it so uh basically I
had um this graphql um API uh that was
um behind authentication and so it was
just for admins right but you could with
a low privilege user just because uh you
know
cookies you could make a simple request
to it but without authorization of
course and um the introspection wasn't
turned on so how do you know which
queries do you do you go to the JS far
right and what I did with Jess whizzle
that was awesome it listed all the
queries I just copied all the queries
and uh generated word list that I gave
to
Clairvoyance uh and basically clance
would try to Force the the schema the
graphical schema and give it back to you
and so then I fit this
70o like it was a big schema uh to
graphical viager and I had like
everything every call that it was being
made because they like in when there is
a graph C everything is always
documented in the front end I don't know
why there is uh some libraries that even
have introspection inside the JS like if
it's not turned out go check the JS and
you can copy the introspection and paste
it just because they forgot to turn turn
a flag seen that yeah i' I've seen like
a lot of times and it's so interesting
um so so it's so funny mention that
because I literally did the exact same
thing I I except I didn't use JS weasel
for it I used my own parsing script to
you know uh expand the webpack files and
then I did exactly that I I took a Rex I
pulled every string that was compliant
with uh graphql um you know naming
standards essentially for for queries
and for um for field names and that sort
of thing I put it all in a word list and
I fed it to Clairvoyance um and for
those of you that are listening that
aren't familiar we'll link it down below
but Clairvoyance is a is a um is a tool
that uh I guess sort of plays on the
problem with a graphql where they will
recommend you uh Fields if you have the
improperly uh defined Fields so uh you
know let's say you there's a field
called store
and you know sometimes it's even like
like pretty pretty far like you might
even get away with like Sport and it
might be did you mean
store it it'll tell you it really
depends on the back end U so depending
on the language uh you can set up U the
amount of token that needs to to be uh
the same
so yeah some sometimes it's like two
tokens apart so two letters sometimes
it's three four uh and they can set up
that on the back end side and depending
on the framework they will have a
different kind of uh far away or not you
know that's yeah well I mean it's really
interesting that you mentioned that that
that strategy with graph because I was I
was going to say the same thing about
not even just graph but same thing with
API requests like yes if you're pulling
apart those webpack uh files and the
lazy loaded files not only will you see
the endpoints but you'll also see how
they're being used where is that data
coming from and one of the really
powerful things about having all of that
just right in front of you in JavaScript
it's just like Android apps where you
know you can decompile it you can see
how everything is working like right in
front of you you can do same thing with
the JavaScript all you have to do is
pull it apart you can see oh it's making
a post request and it builds the body
with these fields that are named this
and that data comes from here it's a
parameter and that's fed in through here
and you can track it all and you can see
sort of how that data flows through the
application to get to that request and
you can piece it together without ever
having used the application at all you
can do it completely from static
analysis yeah
yeah all righty next up is episode 45
the OG bug Bounty King fron Rosen what
an episode that was in this segment that
we chose we're talking about a lot of
good stuff but primarily we're talking
about app cach service workers cookie
stuffing and post message specifically I
remember having an excellent
conversation with frons surrounding
chaining crlf injections with service
workers uh which resulted in some sort
of novel ideas I haven't heard before so
hope you guys enjoy it bringing us back
on track to the to the hacking stuff I
did want to talk about one of my
favorite um talks that you've ever done
which just essentially looked like
prophecy to me looking back in in the
past which is your attacking modern web
Technologies talk that you did in
2018 um uh almost exactly five years ago
yeah um and attacking modern web
Technologies there was so many awesome
pieces to this there was um app caches
and service workers uh you know there
was post message stuff there was upload
policies yeah the the policies the S3
policies all sorts of stuff all over the
place so um once again mandatory
mandatory reading for anybody who's
listening um the crazy thing about to me
about this talk is like this is still
the stuff that we're talking about today
like and this was years ago right it's
still applicable yeah like I find bugs
like like I sometimes I need to go back
to those slides because I find bugs for
those things exactly they have extremely
long lifespan those blog posts I'm
surprised myself that it's like still
working and this is something that's
really I think a key listen and also
help helps for your for your brand as
well fron is that fron was was talking
about this stuff not not only doing this
stuff but talking about it publicly in
2018 five years ago and I I we talk
about post message still being an
underserved technology even to this day
so keep an eye on anything fron releases
because it it it will very likely be
applicable for the future um uh so talk
to me a little bit about uh app cach and
and service worker stuff and then um in
conj Junction with that the beauty of
the synergies between cookie stuffing
and and these Technologies yeah so I
think the the the interesting part with
the app cach uh that that happened there
there were there were many many fun
things with it but H my aspect of it was
that I had a really old Dropbox account
and the old Dropbox account were like
grandfathered
into a place where you could actually
host websit on on Dropbox user
content.com H and you and if you created
a new Dropbox account back then you
couldn't really run your own like you
couldn't Rend the HTML pages and stuff
but if you had a legacy Dropbox account
you could but it was very limited into
what you could actually uh trigger with
it or like get it to to um render um and
I came to the conclusion that like what
can I do with an xss or running an xss
on on Dropbox user content and I I
remember I was talking with Matias then
and like what can we do like can we do
something and we came to the conclusion
like Okay cookie stuffing we can do so
you can make it like unable to actually
load because you're filling up the
cookie jar so much so when you're making
a request later on it will fail so so qu
question here so essentially what was
happening is you were able to host your
uh you know attacker controlled content
on a domain with with other attack you
know victim content on on that same
domain right yeah exactly what happened
was you got like a user directory on
Dropbox user content that you could host
data on uh and then you could uh I think
it was that I can see it now and I'll
I'll reference it it's slide 15 for any
of those of you that are following along
here um you know he's got dld Dropbox
userc content.com you and then the user
ID and then wherever you would update
stuff and you got the xss not by
uploading an HTML file but by using SVG
right well I think it was an XML XML XML
you're right you're right yes XML yeah
so that was the thing everything else
was like you know getting downloaded and
position attachment uh but that was the
way but but if you had a new Dropbox
account you would never get the URL to
to you Dropbox user user content it was
only the Legacy Dropbox account that had
that feature enabled um so that was the
you know the the weird part first with
with having that so we knew that we
could do cookie stuffing and what would
happen then if if somebody else sent a
link that would like four four and or
four of four of five or something I or
five five creators 411 I think maybe
actually yeah so so that concept of of
um cookie stuffing I learned that from
from you and from file descriptor and
and so I'm it file descriptor that that
I learned it from it was from I was
going to ask where did you get that
knowledge and of course it goes back to
another Legend file descriptor yeah file
descriptor man and and the funny thing
with this bug was that I think Matias
was the one mentioning we're coming back
to F script there so yeah he mentioned
appcash and I started reading up on what
appcash was doing and Matias as well and
we started like playing with that and
realized that we could you know host
reference a manifest into in the XML
file that manifest would then be loaded
and that manifest could be like a
regular text or whatever sure and that
text could contain and say that if if
you're unable to reach this website you
should have a fallback your fallback
page of this and that sure because the
whole appcash thing was based on you
running an app and you're going offline
with your cell phone so you need to if
you reload the page you can still visit
it this is crazy and absolutely crazy
and what happened was that we realized
that in our user path we could put an
HTML file or an XML file and we could
say that this is the one that should be
loaded if you can't reach the website
and then we realized okay does the
cookie stuffing result in this thing and
it turns out that yes so we cookie
stuffed and made sure that if you
clicked on any other link we would just
steal the URL and then steal the the
page of that signed URL ourselves that's
amazing but the weird part of was that
when we did this a blog post I don't
know exactly the date wise so our bug to
Dropbox
was here and then here yeah and then
file descriptor comes out with a talk H
explaining this bug and we were like but
we what we what so that that was when we
want we got the Dropbox uh bug published
so we could show that we also figured
this out that's crazy uh and and so so
he actually did a talk on I think on OAS
oasp talk or or something else but and
so we we came to the same kind of
conclusion uh which was great so I
wanted to like highlight that that like
sometimes people can like figure out the
same kind of things at the same time uh
and as you mentioned like there's like
the new thing I think I mentioning it as
well like service workers was a was a
like a a replacement for appcash but
back then I think it was like very hard
to like get a a service worker to work
because yeah you needed to have like a
specific header on the service worker
file to allow it to run as a service
worker
and there were a lot of like if this and
that that that had to work uh to make it
actually exploitable it it seems like
there's there's definitely been some
change in that area now and so um you
know I've definitely seen service
workers used in in lots of different
different context I believe you and I
always have to you know go back and look
at it but I'm not 100% sure but I I I'm
99% sure that service workers can be
installed without a header now and the
header that if you do Supply an HTTP
response header what that will allow you
to do is reassign the uh the root PA the
the the um Authority for that service
worker so if you you know even though
you're installing the service worker at
like sljs sjjs or whatever or swjs um
then then you know you normally just
have Authority for the sljs directory
but if you're able to serve that service
worker allowed I think header um then
you can get
and say Hey give it permission to slash
then you can now affect all the
resources ins everywhere and it's it's
such an interesting technology
especially when you pair it with
something like uh subdomain takeover or
or um you know file upload because you
can gain sort of sort of a persistence
in the browser as well um using service
workers and and um you know that that ex
we've seen this also with truffle
security Rel released a a tool called of
course I'm not sure if you've seen it
fron but it's it's um it uses a service
worker in the background to uh gain more
time to be able to attack different um
websites that have vulnerable cores
configurations even if you just visit
the page for just an instant you know so
there's so many um I think
applicable you know exploitation
scenarios for service workers um that
that we we got to keep our eye on
because they they have tremendous impact
yeah no and I agree but like I I guess
the core concept first is like you need
to have an xss to begin with and and
then you probably need to have arguments
on why that xss wasn't important in the
beginning and I guess like storage like
a bucket storage is a is a is a good
argument on like an xss there doesn't do
anything but if you have persistence you
can like show and I think that was what
the the the bug showed was like it's a
Sandbox domain it doesn't have an impact
but you have persistence and and and
that's the way to like gain access to
other URLs and stuff I just thought
about something France you know one of
the things we're going to talk about a
little bit later assuming we don't have
to cut for time is this middleware
misconfigurations that you you talked
about so what if we change that right
like we we changed the middleware
misconfiguration um and and so now we we
can use that to hit a different bucket
on the so just to be I'm going to give
the tldr of the of the middleware Mis
configuration thing
if you if you essentially with some
enginex configurations if you hit it if
you put a bunch of Escape characters you
know um new lines and stuff like that in
the URL and they have some specific
proxy pass rules um then you will be
able to re rewrite the rest of the
request and hit other S3 buckets or
other backend entities and host your own
content Bas exactly so what if we we
chain that with service workers right um
where you could then hit your own S3
bucket and and issue but I'm I'm
wondering I mean you still have stored
stored xss I guess like somebody needs
to visit your url still and and that one
would still make you host whatever
content you want on that website so the
but the the thing you're gaining is the
pers the the persistent thing that you
can actually make it load but they still
need to visit it once can you can you
I'm wondering though can
you set response headers in
S3 yeah it depends if it's S3 website
you can some of them uh but I mean you
could also if it's S3 website you can
still redirect it to whenever like and
depending on like the CSP for example
you can still redirect it elsewhere I
don't know if that helps you though no
no because what I'm thinking is like
wouldn't it be cool if we
could insert some some new line
characters over right the the backend
bucket right have the bucket serve a a
service worker and then insert the
service worker header to slash so now so
we we we gain you know that service
worker Authority um and get xss stored
xss on every single page that the user
visits within the browser I think that
could be really cool I mean S3 website
would uh allow you to do this if it's if
an S3 website uh is if it's proxying you
to S3 website and you can inject
something to modify what bucket it's
going to serve as a website you can
inject whatever head you want the host
cuz I wonder I wonder if if we are
hitting so let's say they're sending a
request to you know whatever. s3. Amazon
aws.com and then we overwrite the host
header on that I wonder if it uses that
same load balancer or gen IP for you to
insert a header to hit S3 websites like
if you if you put in it doesn't okay no
h S3 website is also quirky because it
only responds on HTTP and not https oh
what uh
I have no idea why I think it has
something to do with like you're
supposed to put it behind something else
kind of cloud front or whatever but so
they they don't have the same load
balancer and you can't really get to S3
website from S3 a far as I know weird
yeah that's that's definitely it's very
isolated it's like a totally it's like
an overlay over F3 it's like s website
is like its own thing that renders
whatever you want basically yeah we'll
definitely have to research that
Thea that I was thinking this could be
interesting is with CRF injection into
the response headers right if you can do
response
splitting assign the service worker
allowed header then you can make a
service worker out of the response
splitting yeah sure that would be pretty
you need something to load it I mean you
could probably make two crlf one crlf to
load a fake document and one crlf that
loads a fake service worker with the
header to install absolutely that should
work yeah sure that's that's that's some
good that's some good [__] right there
um that's fun then you get persistence
yeah huh I'm just I'm thinking about all
the possibilities can see the gears
turning in soon as he hangs up he's G
he's got three programs he's got to go
look at then you then you and then you
can probably you know escalate it to you
know steal access tokens and stuff and
yeah I mean U you can probably do things
with that and it it makes it a lot
more it makes it I
mean it's a little bit interesting right
because technically what that could
result in then is we could get plain we
could leak the user's plain text
password without user interaction right
because like like you said what what are
we actually what we what do we actually
gain from this because at that point if
we have stored xss right then we can
just open up whatever Pages we want in
an iframe and then do whatever we want
right do whatever yeah but but one of
the things that we can't do is is
without more entry user interaction is
leak the user's plain text password
assuming they don't have any crazy thing
but but due to the persistence you can
uh you can get them to yeah sure which
which really escalates pretty much
any and then I guess it's a reflected
more than stored but you turn it into
more of a stored a client side stored a
client side stored xss client side
stored that's really interesting and
then and then this this is a really good
um atto mechanism because some
especially if you then proceed to cookie
bomb like a a a specific path that that
issues you know an off token or
something like that it forces the user
to to clear their cookies and re off the
next time that they they go into the
application and at that point if you've
got the service worker you can hijack
the the plane text password yeah we this
is this is some good I think to get you
on this podcast more
this is great no no no this is really
good okay so um wow as much as I would
like to sit there and just uh think on
that for the next little while let's
let's try to keep rolling um it's
probably a sin but I'm going to skip
this whole uh section on um S3 policies
and Cloud policy uploads which is a
really awesome part of of the attacking
modern web Technologies uh talk and I'm
going to jump to something that we've
talked a little bit more about on the
podcast uh often which is
um the the post message stuff um so
uh how did you because I once again
you're one of the one of the first
people that I I you know sort of
introduced me to post message stuff yeah
where where did you how did you come up
with this and then what what was it like
you know sort of seeing this did
somebody else's research spur this
thought in you or was it just how does
this work sort of that's that's a really
good question remember I guess it's the
first question no I I don't I I actually
don't 100% remember where I think I
think like this I think there were
examples of vulnerable cases already
post like I wasn't the one showing that
you can exploit it uh but I started to
so I think I did a lot of focus back
then on I think it was Dropbox maybe
yeah and I think it was so it was also
like payment providers there was
something because payment providers tend
to do a lot of and you had to talk
yourself about it yeah yeah and and what
happened was that there was a as a as a
huge amount of payment providers that
started moving over to post message and
you always had a really hard part
finding all the post message listeners
so as I did back then I was discussing
with Matias like what how how do we
figure these things out and and we came
to the conclusion that like okay
probably an extension and then I sat
down and wrote a bunch of like you know
inside eye frames deep you know H post
message that that get listeners that get
triggered by actions and and a lot of
different I think it's still in the
repository there's like an example. HTML
with a bunch of listeners and and just
to like try to figure out what we can do
about it and I I I made my first uh
version of the of the extension and like
okay this will be usable like oh just
the number even though you have like
five if frames deep a listener the
number counter on the post message
listener Chrome extension will still you
know increase uh versus looking at the
The Source events Global events and you
only see the iframe you're currently
selected yeah I was like this is a
terrible functionality uh so I made my
first version of this and I I talked
with the Google team because I told them
like why can't you just like I don't
want to start building an extension like
can't you just fix so you can see all
the listeners in all eye frames yeah and
they're like no this is how it's
supposed to be and blah blah blah and
it's terrible and it's something
something that I talked about in my talk
as well but like yeah you got to do your
due in and you still even have to do
your due diligence to go and show where
all of the you know to to go sus all of
the listeners because something may not
be utilizing that listener right so
in that Cas it won't show up in post
Mage tracker so you still got to go
through and do it one of you know it's
my fault is as well because I haven't
contributed to that nice private repo
you put me on for for post message
tracker but I think it would be really
cool to to add a a line that that shows
every time a post message tracker is
registered and where it's registered so
so you you know just like you get a
request where you know you get a log in
your console when it gets sent through
um a post message is sent through you
can also get a log when one is
registered so you can know okay well the
you know
my uh child Windows third if frame has
registered a launch a listener that that
could be really cool because that attack
surface is all over the place like you
mentioned absolutely and and I would say
the most common ones I found nowadays
are the ones not initiated from from
start but by action yeah so they they
just because you so I have an example in
one talk I did on in Amsterdam for like
a live hacking event basically what
happened was that when you clicked on
upload document there was a listener
started at that action and then you
could do whatever you could basically
read whatever document you uploaded you
could read it from the sandbox uh but
but so there's a bunch of those like
action-based listeners that gets
triggered by things and what I've seen
late like lately also and I think one of
the biggest trick
that up my sleeve with the post Mage
listener was the unpacking of the
rappers Yeah so basically everything is
wrapped through New New Relic or roll
bar or there's a bunch of those but and
jQuery also has its own wrapper but the
way of figuring out how to bypass the
wrapper and then go directly to the
function so you can G get like the real
function that is actually being
triggered that was I think the the
Golden Nugget in in the extension that
is that that was really helpful and what
I've seen lately now is like people
using message ports which is like an
addition to to post message where you
send an initial post message with a port
and that Port can then be you know you
can Shuffle that Port between iframes uh
but the one having the port is the one
getting the messages yeah dude I'm so
glad you mentioned that because I just
found my first you know bug using
message ports in a live hacking event
Maybe well I won't say exactly when
because because that'll give it away but
but within the past year right um and
and it was uh it was very interesting
and I think one of the things that that
was crazy there is it it sometimes
people will just get a port and then
they'll just shove data into it without
doing you know or origin checks or
anything like that too and so you know
it actually even creates more complexity
and more room for vulnerabilities when
when you're utilizing the message Port
stuff yeah and it's fun because you can
you can have a message Port from one
little if frame and if you get hold of
that message Port you can take it into a
different if frame and then the the the
window thinking it sends sends it to the
if frame is actually sending it cross
domain somewhere else so yeah that
message Port can be you can juggle that
message Port wherever you want which is
kind of funny that it's like just a
connection it's basically like a a
socket that you can that shuffles data
it's I'm also kind of surprised that we
haven't seen more post m message based
tooling out there like maybe I'm just
naive but your post message tracker is
pretty much the only extension that I've
seen that that does anything like this
so um one thanks for doing that because
otherwise you would have no
introspection iuse I use it every day
myself it's my the only probably
extension I use myself and every every
day I'm looking at it so it's like I'm
that it's a good example of like writing
something that would you would use
yourself yeah and it's 100% like that
like it doesn't go a day without me
looking at I I'd kind of like also to
just to highlight you
know the importance of understanding
browser mechanics and stuff like that so
let's say for example you you you know
post message stuff was just coming out
or something like that right and you go
to a page and you see a an iframe open
up or or not an i frame a popup you know
open
up and it does something and then it re
you know that change somehow seems to
appear back on the on the original
window right and you don't see any HTTP
requests so it's not pushing it out to
the server and not coming back right so
you're like wait a second how the heck
is this working because if you have a an
understanding of browser mechanics you
you know you need you need some sort of
reference to pass it and that sort of
thing same origin kind of works still
yeah same origin is fine for that yeah
so it's important to understand you know
if it's happening cross origin like that
you can't just you know say parent you
know or opener do you know window you
know whatever and just Define variables
or trigger call backs in the parent
window if it's cross origin so so having
the a strong understanding of same
origin policy having a strong um
understanding of of um window references
you know that those sort of things are
essential to be able to identify these
sort of issues um as the technology
evolves absolutely and I think I one one
thing that I I I did some talks on it
but I think
is there will be a lot more bugs on it
it's it's client side race conditions
with post message I I think that's I
think I was early on with it uh but I
think that there are much more places to
investigate that might be similarly
vulnerable to it I I don't have so I've
got a couple client side race conditions
um in place um bugs that I found and I'm
actually doing some research on them
right now uh which I'll share with you
after this after this chat um and maybe
we can collab on it because uh the
implications of it are pretty gnarly um
but uh it's I need to do what you did
with ol 30 dancing and just like you
know work through all the all the
pathways work with all the pathways to
it but yeah I mean there there's so many
things that can be said about that one
piece that is not super relevant to the
to the um to the bug that the or to the
research that I'm talking about is the
the concept of client side raci
condition
via post message when um one of the
people is using json.parse
so the thing about json.parse is that it
it when you're parsing that that Json
data from a string back into a Json
object that takes
computational power to to load up all
those objects right so I had a scenario
when I was getting a post message at two
different windows at the same time right
and I needed to be so this window was
Rel the first window that would receive
the post message was relaying it to me
the attacker but then that first window
would respond to the post message and
set some configuration settings right so
I had to receive it you needed a message
to be first but you also needed to read
it faster than the other exactly so the
F the first window that received it was
using Json pars yeah string matching I
guess exactly I used I used just
substring right to extract this this
variable that I needed to send the
message and was able to win the race
back to the first window that's awesome
and and so uh that's a that's a cool
little little TI those things are are
beautiful Json pars is a little bit um
computationally also also I think like
the whole concept of sending uh object
like arbitrary objects I know F scripter
made one of those using blob yeah uh but
there there are a bunch like you can
send the Rix object yeah and and so
there's a bunch of these like if this is
not a string kind of bu that you can
find just because you're sending a
completely different object with post
message uh I think it's like file blob
reg there's a bunch of more that you can
uh you can send over wow I didn't know
that actually I got to look into that
and I know that some some providers have
implemented Frameworks where like
serialization and deserialization
Frameworks that just make my life
terrible they are crazy I know I know
exactly what you mean I've seen those as
well it takes a lot lot of time but
sometimes in those cases I I rather look
for the the SNS first exactly or like
like is is it even you
know time to go down this path yeah
exactly no totally those are
tricky for our last interview clip this
is with Mr fall down the well himself
Matias a beden Brun Carlson uh this is
just a spectacular part of the episode
where he talks all about xslt and M xss
mutation xss and all the sorts of
tooling and interesting intricacies with
care sets and all sorts of really really
cool stuff make sure to check this one
out Char
sets no Char sets car car Char sets
probably Char sets either way enjoy the
episode so a part of my research for the
technical [__] section is um going
through every tweet you've ever tweeted
and finding all the interesting stuff
and uh talk getting ready to talk about
that so you put out this Tool
uh hack a
planet uh no it's it's hack the planet
in Swedish can you say it hack Planet
Haka
plantin I don't know man I have the L
sish someday that's great you own that
domain the SE domain and HTML parse and
it this is super awesome so essentially
what it does you go to this this thing
here you submit an HTML document and
then it runs D purify on it it and it
puts it through all of these
um different serers side HTML renderers
and shows you the result um so tell me
why you did this and can you well first
explain you're looking for mutation xss
here
apparently why are you looking for
mutation xss and what is mutation
xss okay so mutation xss is like
if you take a payload and just give it
to the browser no no alert box will pop
essentially but if you put it through
some parser first like even one that's
inside of the browser itself which is M
says like right inner
HTML uh setting or like the D parer um
Etc and then it will essentially try to
fix errors and in the markup and while
inserting those fixes it
actually turns it into like SS let's say
so so if I'm understanding
correctly the browser or the the sort of
I guess Dom rendering engine whatever it
is it could be a serers side HTML parser
could be a browser could be you know
some other modif modification within the
browser when
you give it some HTML document that is
not spec compliant typically right you
know it it it will look at this thing
and say okay can't render this because
it's not spec compliant let me see what
I can do to fix it and when it does that
it will inadvertently cause xss is that
right yeah that's exactly right it's a
bug in the I'll fix your bad markup love
that thank you for your help uh browsers
and Dom renders all around we we love
that you we can rely on you for this
sort of thing so so what was the
motivation for this tool man what did
you why did you build this and what kind
of stuff have you been finding with it
well the motivation was it actually had
nothing to do with
xss
but yeah well it was
like it was like a XML bug but I know
they accepted you it was weird because
you could send HTML to it instead of XML
and I was like hm I wonder what parer
they're using because there were certain
Tes they wouldn't allow me to use and I
needed them to exploit stuff yeah and I
had this idea like I wonder if I can
hide the tags from them somehow but when
it forwards it it will actually be
unhidden
because some other parts are where it
actually ends up after that treats in a
different way so I was like okay how how
surely there's some tool you can just
spin up all of these things and see like
how do each part par it Sur and it's
like nope and then standard moment in
all its life oh man someone should build
this I'm not someone I guess I'm
someone so that's great man so you you
went and you built it you took how many
geez I mean you press Parson here and it
just keeps on going so you've got so
many 16 parsers of them wow dude how
much of a pain in the but was that to uh
to do I mean the biggest problem was uh
choosing whether I
should Implement like a whole web stack
for it or if I should make like a hack
which I ended up doing
like do I need to make have like a web
server and a whole MDC framework just to
call this paring function and see what
it
does U but instead do built it with
Apache and CGI actually and then it will
just run like C version of the wow very
cool man yeah so that's I took the shops
about this actually which way to do it
in in a practical way because I'm like
it's gonna take a long time if I'm gonna
have to build an actual application he
that is dude oh I see you open sourced
it too yeah yeah yeah so that's what I
did and uh oh it's got a Docker it's got
dude I did not see this when I did the
research this this uh no each each one
of them is it's own Docker container no
dude and then he so okay okay so you've
got it in a Docker container and then
you can literally just do Echo your your
your Dom pipe it into Docker exec and
then give it the name of the parcel you
want and it'll just do
it yeah that's dude this is so you can
like f it through that if you like to or
you can use the
the beautiful web interface this is
really well architected dude I'm really
impressed nice nice work with this do
you have any um so did you did you pop
thatl or no I did I did and like uh
because I I managed to uh
hide tags with it because it pared the
um HTML comments incorrectly so it
didn't recognize dash dash
exclamation great downam as an end of a
comment ah but you can also like
okay if you if you view on like of
in that's like a I have put in like a
combination of those things that I found
for different Parcels that will like
hide the content of the document oh up
up at the top there is that no what do
you like um on just the homepage of of.
I see if you take for example just
standard uh beautiful soup and H and and
you try to scrape my site and like take
the links you cannot do it no way
really and it's same with like
Flo a couple hours but um so yeah that
was like the second like interesting
challenge I thought of when building
that's just like H I wonder if we can
hide
[Music]
from from scrapers like what inflations
can't can't be the good old red
though that's true that's true yeah no
that's really cool though I love that
you built that in that's like some
serious hacker hacker [__] right there
when you like make your own you
implement this on your own website just
for the kicks yeah so that they can't
you know pull your LinkedIn and your
Twitter from aen br. that's high value
high value links you've got there only
for human
eyes yeah no no so I did find some stuff
and I have been thinking about the
implementing like the same with XML
forers to too because that's something
that I that I
think could have specific bugs too like
someone wants a research
area pick a bunch of different
standardized xal parsers see how they
treat like exteral types or other type
of xxc
issues and play around with it because
there was someone in in the
Thinking podcast actually I don't think
they meant what I thought they meant but
they gave me an idea that like okay
maybe there's a par that doesn't require
the doct Declaration to be at the start
of the document
and I saw that conversation that looked
interesting but but that would make
xxc like a new type of XC I guess which
would be like external doct type inject
so when when you're injecting into the
body of the XL instead controlling whole
things so I actually have a a piece of
research that I want to say I don't
remember whether I actually put it into
the samle episode for for critical
thinking but there is a Chrome browser
exploit that was a couple weeks ago not
the one that that dropped in the
critical thinking research uh xx1
recently um
where they were using xslt
transforms yeah to do some crazy stuff
with the placement of that entity you
know the dock type tag um and so there
essentially it was like it was using the
parser to stick it up at the top and on
one on the first parser it would it
would not have it at the top and on the
next one it would and then trigger the
xxt um so the other cool thing you can
do with that is the xslt transform
which I am really excited to dive into
deep more I hope I hope some of the
listeners go and do this research
because I I'm super swamped with stuff
right now but I would love to see any
research research on xslt maybe I can
nerd snipe you on it dude the transforms
are so cool I did have you have you like
learned it all about xslt transforms
yeah yeah I found exslt bug one and a
half week ago oh my gosh of course you
have all right whatever whatever Matias
all right we're but that it was one and
half week ago so it means I forgot yeah
your your context window is
gone no that's great man so all right
well then so you've actually done some
more Hands-On stuff with it than I have
because I've just done mostly reading
and ideating on it um what is your yeah
share sh share a little bit about that
would
you I can share about that but I just it
was really interesting point that you
brought up with this XLT because xslt is
basically meant to like transform the
incoming XML document to something else
so it's pre transform it you can
transform it into something that now has
X in it that's yeah I I guess that's
what you meant but I have to revisit it
because it's awesome that's great man I
can see you he's for those of you that
are are listening not watching on
YouTube there's like this far off look
in his eyes that is the the the mark of
of a bug forming I can see it that's
great man I love that um yeah there's
also a lot of stuffff or there are
different couple of different exlt
libraries but you can do like file
system stuff yeah to and get like
environment variables and stuff so you
can even do more stuff than with just
normal yeah 100% And so yeah I'd like to
normally before people come in the
podcast I message them and I say hey you
know check out this document you know
that sort of thing right and then I also
tell them hey bring a bug or two so that
we can talk about it on the Pod and I
totally forgot to do that for you for
this episode so I'm sorry about that we
talk about that one yeah can you can you
give us some info on that that'd be
great uh so that one was you could
upload an XML okay through a bunch of
different Hoops you had to jump through
but it ended with like you could provide
an XML and then in another place you
could provide the
xslt
document
and the funny thing is the xslt document
is also specified as XML right and and
that that one was vulnerable to xsc but
I didn't find it because I tried it in
the original document that was not
vulnerable so then I was like okay xslt
I'm going to learn it xslt specific buxs
and then like after I played with it and
talk to France about it but this is 6C
freaking dude shut up shut up fron like
get out of here who invited you to this
anyway
but in another way so
one Noel trick that I learned with that
was that I forget exactly what the
operation was called but there's like a
couple of ways you can read files and
you can read Json files with one
operation I can try and write it later
we can we can link to this documentation
yeah
write or sorry you can read XML
documents but you can also read raw
files yeah but the problem
is oh this is connecting to the next
part actually of this secret document
you could
also in the parer you weren't allowed to
read read the mtes into the the
resulting document like oh damn can't
read like Pro Environ yeah separated
Windows uh but what you could do is
specify the in
of the file so what you could do is you
could tell it treat it
as like youf 16 example and then it
would spit out like a bunch of Chinese
characters and then you could like
transform that
back and I knew that it was a Java
application so I could just use ha
worker and then know that it's like Java
versus Ja so I actually exed like the
environment via like reading the file
as in and then turn it back dude that is
you've been doing so much crazy Char set
stuff lately man that's that's really
cool you bypass that with that though
that's that's an amazing idea I like I
like I
suppose typ confusion bugs yeah like
it's a broad area they are my one of my
favorites and en coding is like I I'm
still not entirely sure I there's a
Block B actually I I can link to it too
it's like really old like 2007 or
something sure and it's called something
like everything you need to know about
encodings and short sets as a developer
okay I need that okay so yeah yeah and
it starts from the beginning like in the
beginning there was a and we that there
was the ask and then like the high bites
was not used for anything and then
so people started implementing whatever
they wanted over
like ZX Al and uh that wasn't really
standardized but then IBM was like okay
we all take all of them and we give the
each a code page number so now when you
see like a short set it's like cp12 34
yeah that's that's the code page wow
dude that's that's cool man I would love
to read that document I think that I
think a lot of our listeners would love
to read that too so I'll um we'll I'll
follow up with you after that and try to
try to get that in the description yeah
um
encoding box is
really really really interesting too and
also things
like injecting like bite order
Mark to
confuse injecting
what bite order Mark oh B tells yeah so
you can use it in likef 16 for example
or like is this encoding flip it around
thing like the left to right
override yeah exactly it's it's like if
it's little l or big like should the top
bite come first or second oh oh yeah
yeah yeah so you're talking about like
um like UTF 16 Le UTF 16 be is that what
you're talking about exactly exactly so
if you have say UTF 16 right then it's
ambiguous you can start the the document
or the string of strings yeah with with
like it ispite order Which F FF I think
for one of them and and then then it's
like aha you're telling it to what
coding it okay so hold on wait a second
so you can actually put that in the
data yeah
what B order
Mark
order dang dude I need a bigger notepad
for this episode um bite order Mark and
so you can put that in the data and it
will Define how the rest of that data
string is
red it should have to start with it
but I wouldn't be surprised if some
people or some interpreters ofers could
have it in the
middle holy crap that's amazing that is
that is super I'm just kind of yeah now
now I've got the thing in my you know
I'm looking off into the into the
distance and and ideating on on what
what could become of that that's that's
really really interesting dude I'm
definitely going to have to look into
that after this um yeah thanks so much
for sharing that I'm sure that'll result
in a bunch of in a bunch of bugs um yeah
there's also some encodings that have
special I don't think it's called bite
order marks but it's like speci special
sequence of characters that like
transform it so like in the middle of
the document you can have bite blah and
blah and then this TS it to like okay
now it's this other way of interpreting
it and it ends with something
else there is encoding s is like okay
now it's f everything is fine no now it
is not now it's this other thing dude
that is so interesting so if you could
get them to parse it with that charet
then you could really use that to bypass
some security controls because you know
whatever parer will be looking at it and
being like okay you know this is just
meaningless text and then when the
actual end you know program runs it it's
something completely different because
it's it's actually parsing the charet
differently yeah yeah exactly so if they
have like a screen contains for example
then it could
be different dude this has got to be do
this was a topic too in the Discord I
saw like normalization they can like
transform it into yeah some some other s
this is this is very and you know of
course my mind goes directly to web
servers and reverse proxies and wafs and
this is actually pretty much exactly
what Sam herb and I were talking about
and I don't know if you saw it in the
document but I I did a talk on this at
Defcon um
on how you can Define host headers for
some uh for some HTTP servers and you
can Define them in different encodings
right so literally our exploit for this
bug was host and this is a host header
host colon equals question mark ISO
8859-1 question mark q and then a bunch
of hex data and that actually got
converted into our exploit on on the the
back end of that um server that we were
talking to it bypassed the enginex uh
configuration that had some limits on
the host header characters being used
and allowed us to inject right into the
engine X config file on the back end
because of the way that we could smuggle
characters like a space and stuff like
that into the host header um and so now
I'm thinking like man there's got to be
even more possibilities of this sort of
thing W with stuff that can change
mid you know mid uh midf flow and change
into something else because maybe the
engine X proxy on the front end reads
decodes the character set but the one on
the back end doesn't and it doesn't
normalize it and then it just treats it
like normal text and then you can pop
xss or you can you know bypass any sort
of filtering in
place yeah but like you also need
to you when you're talking about excess
you need either you need service side
normalization for it to transform
because when you're sending like you're
using that's 16% what what you're
actually sending is just two bites and
and if you want like a less than
characters those two bites will be no
bite and 3C so if it filters 3C in like
an 8 bit as encoding it would go like
okay is this a this
a yes and so you need need normalization
or you need some kind of encoding
supported in the client that where
like 03 C or
033 f means less than I'm wondering if
there's other there's got to be other
encodings besides you know UTF 8
utf16 that put those at different code
points right in browsers no well you
know and I linked actually funny you
mentioned that Matias because I did my
homework for this episode and if you
click the first the first link under the
character set
um heading in the secret document I have
a link directly to the chromium source
code in all of the different um uh
character encodings that we you know
that can be used in here and I see one
of them you know is this ISO 8859-1 that
I'm famili more familiar with from the
the Defcon talk and so I'm wondering if
there's different ways you know or any
of these different encodings put a
different put the you know less than
sign or greater than sign or whatever at
a different code point so that if if if
it it bypasses the front end and says
okay you know the front end says this is
uh you know a question mark But the back
end says okay I'm actually not reading
this as as you know Windows D1 you know
1252 and actually I'm I'm interpreting
this as utf8 or interpreting this as
aski and then you know you get the
output as an actual script tag does that
does that make sense or am I thinking
about this
incorrectly I mean it's a good idea but
the iso
8859 yeah it's different is no it is es
based no no I know I know it's not what
we're it it doesn't meet the standards
of what we're we're looking at yeah but
but is there is something like that then
yes unfortunately I don't think that
there
is
uh any nony supported tets for like H
dangerous
content so the the overlap they used to
be they used to be yeah yeah especially
like internet had some special cases and
like all of them at some points for the
uf7 which is just like seven seven so
asky aski would be so the base for all
of these is what you're saying so the
first 256 characters of every single one
that 3C is always going to be the the
angle bracket for for xss
yeah is the all the characters you need
and pation for the English language so
it starts at serx 20 and stopped at at
at
the S like small letter see yeah at
least that's how I learn in my
room all right and we are on to the Bug
Story section so in this clip from
episode 27 we're going to be talking
about the AET note share file rce uh
specifically there was an authentication
bypass relating to the padding in as 256
so make sure to check this clip out yeah
yeah I mean it's always they're always
anytime you see a block post from Acid
note it's always very high quality and
it goes into a ton of detail about like
their thought methodology and the path
that they took to get there and they do
a really good job of explaining sort of
like the attacker mindset as they're
coming towards something that like from
the title you can tell is very severe um
you know it's an rce so I think that
provides sort of a unique insight and
oftentimes it's not like the super
straightforward type of like oh I put
like ID like and ID in in a Cory
parameter and it pops you know like it's
usually a little bit more in depth and
it goes into like how they discovered it
and the files that they were looking for
and the patterns and stuff and I think
like that's really useful because a lot
of times you see sort of like the
blackbox approach where it's like I was
just fuzzing this endpoint I saw an
interesting parameter I tried a command
injection and it worked and that's it
and you don't really get the
understanding for like what that looks
like on the on the back end or like the
engineering side or like if you were
doing Source carde review how that might
um how that might look and so I think uh
it's really awesome to see the blog post
that they put out because they go into
that level of detail yeah for sure as
always I love the methodology in the
write up they they talk about they dump
all the files they they talk about um
this this uh I guess function that's
getting called to parse the cookie Set
current principle from session cookie um
which you know if you were just kind of
looking through the code you might
assume that that is going to be
something that does you know auth an
authentication check and in fact the
title of that section they they titled
authenticated but not really um because
that once you double click into that
that you know that call it just skips
over it if it doesn't find the cookie
that it was looking for um and so it's
like okay well sort of that was going to
be an authentication check and there's
some other pieces down the line where um
you know you would assume authentication
was was um was necessary but they kind
of you know weave around out of those
and eventually end up finding a path
traval not in um let me see if I can
find the name of the parameter it's not
in the parameter that you would think um
here it is right here yeah so it's it's
not in the parameter that allows you to
specify the path it's a it's a in the uh
upload ID parameter um and that gets
concatenated with the path a little bit
later and even though the path is
actually um sanitized uh the uh upload
ID is not which meaning which results in
the path traval which allowed them to
get arbitrary file right so that was a
really I think that was a really good
method and then the this one also sort
of has a little bit of an A A Twist to
it which is you need to have a a valid
parent ID within the application and so
that parent ID um you might assume would
be something you might have to have like
a valid folder or a valid um you know ID
of a folder or something but really they
found that all you have to do is have a
um string that does not fail when it
gets uh AES decrypted and so it doesn't
matter what that string is it's not used
anywhere but if it if it is if it gets
uh you know if it passes the ases
decryption then you're able to to do the
attack so they they outline really well
um how AES Works how um the pkcs uh 7
padding works and how they were able to
use that to um really reliably guess a
value for this um curent ID I think it
was only 128 or 256 um tries that it
took to brute force and then they find a
a valid value that will pop and result
in them getting a shell so once again
you know big round of applause to the
Asen team they they killed
it yeah yeah I think it's um it's really
interesting because this is a something
that we talk about in app appc a lot
where it's like validation versus
verification and a like to like a
textbook example is JWT tokens where
they're just checking is this a valid
JWT token not is the contents inside of
the JWT token valid and so those are two
very different things like if you're
just checking that this is a valid JWT
token it can decode properly and that's
it and you're not actually checking who
signed it or is the key correct and is
the person who they're saying they are
in the JWT token actually who they who
they are like if you're not doing those
checks then that's where these little
like weird weird edge cases because you
might read through this and I'm sure
like whoever wrote this like didn't
think that this was going to be an issue
they probably were like yeah just you
know check if this is valid and go
forward and that's not enough you need
to like also just verify like do that
extra step and that that Pitfall I think
hits in a lot of different areas um and
you know this is just another example of
you know in a big product as well like
just that classic kind of case where
they checked it but they didn't fully
verify it yeah I don't know about on the
the JWT front I kind of feel like that's
the whole cell of the JWT though is that
like you know it should be sort of
self-authenticating because it's signed
by the you know by the person that that
has the private key right so you know
and obviously that doesn't always work
out to be the case but um you know these
different Technologies do have their
different pitfalls and that is you know
in the JWT scenario as you mentioned
that if somebody does you know find a
way to forge a token or get their hands
on the private key or whatever then
you're just totally screwed so yeah yeah
so much of that comes down to like which
Library you're using too like if you're
just using a library that separates out
like validation and verification then
that might just like put you in a big
Pitfall where you're using the built-in
library or something but it has an extra
function that you needed to call and you
didn't know it or something like that
and that oftentimes is just either a
documentation problem or something even
stupider than that and you know it it
happens to everybody so I think it's
just a you know it's cool to see it in
the wild and I think it's just something
that you should always keep keep an eye
out for and just like you know check and
see are they are they actually verifying
my my JWT contents can I just give it
any sign JWT and will it work yeah so um
I guess bringing it back to the blog
post I did have one more thing that I'll
just try to explain from you know
without you having to go and read the
blog post which is like I I've done a
couple deep Dives on AES and um and you
know the p portion of it for padding
Oracle attacks so for those of you that
have done that in the past and want a
little bit of a refresher the way that
the uh
pkcs7 padding works is that you've got
your you know you've got your 16 uh byte
blocks and then when you don't have when
your data does not sum up to 16 bytes
the rest of that 16 bytes is filled by
the value that is the number of
remaining bytes so if youve got 15 uh
you know bytes in that in that block and
you need to get one more that last bite
is going to contain the a bite that
points to one and if it's you know 14
then it's going to have two yeah zero
0202 right um and so that that's
something that I had back there you know
in in the memory database and that but
just doesn't come you know sometimes
when I need it to so there's your little
refresher on on um AES uh padding
protocol for any of you that are
interested in that that low level of
cryptography yeah yeah yeah you probably
see this a lot in ctfs too like if you
decrypt an as block and it's not exactly
the block length then it'll always have
like trailing bites that usually are not
printable because it's from like 0x01 to
0x0f and so oftentimes you'll be like oh
what is that oh right I need to unpad it
and there's like a some copy paste
function that I always use off stack
Overflow to do that in Python yeah yeah
no python man this is just another great
example because the exploit here is
written in Python is like you really if
you're going to try to get to this level
of you know Pro hacking you need to be
pretty handy with python or you know
some sort of scripting language so that
you can just write out these PC's pretty
quickly all righty next up is one of my
favorite clips from all of our ctbb
podcasting from this last year a clip in
which I get to talk to Alex Chapman
himself about a bug that I duped him on
in Alex Chapman bug one of the finest
accomplishments of my bug Bounty career
this is the Force rce um hope you guys
enjoy this one I most certainly did this
this was a bug at a live hacking event
um earlier this year and it was a
rce that and and this is the thing that
makes me sad too is that um this is a a
blog post that Alex wrote up on on a
specific vulnerability and a specific
protocol uh per force and um and I you
know using to be fair to myself using
other resources and Al 's blog um I
found you know an rce on this on this
target this shared Target that we had
and um and then uh I submitted the
report before Alex
did so he duped he and we split the
Bounty right because it's a live hacking
event dupe but um uh you know it was one
it was a really um a great example of
the way that Alex Alex thinks and and
what we were talking about earlier with
blogging about things that you're
passionate about um and a perfect
example of this client server trust um
sort of situation that we have because
that's where the vul was um but and Alex
I I don't recall whether I sent you this
specific vulnerability before we started
uh recording the podcast do you want to
talk to the technical details of this
vul uh did you do you have the it fresh
enough in your mind or do you want me to
take a stab at it and you can kind of
supplement yeah I think of um I've
actually been looking at again recently
for something else so it it is to okay
all right
it's talk us through it this is an
interesting one but it's again so for
those who don't know perforce is a
version control system so similar to git
or um SN that's heavily used in the
gaming industry because it's it works
really well with very large files um so
if you got really large assets 3D models
that sort of thing
um and it it it's a very typical example
of the
the client trust that we mentioned
before so all the um perforce client
really does is connect to the server and
the server then says run this
command and then so the server will say
okay show me what files you've got check
the hashes of the files against the
files I've got so rather than it being
client controlled it's server controlled
um and that that was the first thing
that kind of got my interest I like well
how does it do how does it give you new
files that you don't have on your system
and it turns out it just sends a uh I
think the command is literally send file
or um right file client Dash right file
is what I have in my report right here
which is just gold like I love that
sounds interesting yeah
um so then seeing that like okay right
how how are we going to go about about
testing this so what do you do break out
Python and then start trying to reverse
engineer the protocols that's going on
the wire and wi shark and building it up
bite by bite bit by bit uh to a point
where I pretty much had a fully
functioning um purle server written in
Python um to kind of handle the orth do
all the rest of it to get it to the
point um where with just a login it
would be able to write an arbitary file
on the on the connecting
system and and that was great so then I
think just in saying this this B cision
on the life hacking event I I kind of
have a bit of a Blas
attitude to submitting these bugs that I
don't think anybody else is going to
submit in life back events and this one
I wasn't going to submit in the dup
period I was like nobody's gonna find
that so oh dude that would have been a
nightmare man I'll prove it after the
dup period closes because nobody else
will find it and I was like I've got a
little bit of time I'll get it in holy
moly and then when I found out it been
was like oh yeah start submitting
everything yeah right as soon as it was
duped I went to the TR I was like um can
you let me know who DED who who was
it I want to have a word it was it was
um and and it was I want to say on your
team as well they took you guys took
bets on who it was right and and fre who
who was it that guessed it was me one of
them correctly guessed that it was me
was it yeah Douglas I want to say it was
Douglas as well yeah so I appreciated
that vote of confidence it is a
uh one of the highest honors in my bug
Bounty career to have duped an Alex jman
bug um so I'm sorry for using your own
blog post against you but um yeah I
completely forgotten I'd written that to
be honest so uh you really no way you
didn't even reference back to it when
you when you had oh my gosh wow that's
crazy UMES and and so I just wanted to
go to what you were saying you know you
wrote out a full a full perfor server
and I'm looking at my exploit right now
and uh you know I I I love that
experience of writing out you know like
a binary level protocol um for these
sort of things and you know you said
that handles the oth and stuff like that
I'm looking at my code and it you know
handles the Au it's just like yeah yeah
yeah don't mind that you know like you
know it connects to the server you're
like no no no it's fine yes yes you got
it correct you know like and then and
then you just yeah yes you're we're
connected here's the code run uh and
it's just a it's just a fun
vulnerability type for
sure all right and you've made it to the
very last clip probably if this is in
order unlikely this is unlikely maybe
otherwise welcome to the middle of the
video or something this is from episode
48 uh an awesome episode with the mvh
Defcon uh black badge earner googler Sam
herb Sam is talking about an XSL tbug
that he found and it's just a really
awesome story so make sure to listen to
this one so I mentioned um on the samel
podcast a while back that uh Sam was one
of the first people that introduced me
to
xslt um and so Sam I was wondering if
you could share a little bit about that
bug and yeah just kind of talk to us
about that yeah so this was at this is
like one of the first life hacking
events I attended and uh there was this
Endo that accepted
um it was XML but it wasn't XML it's
xslt which is like a data transformation
language okay so it accepted uh xslt
directly yes um but it it would accept
like it was like you would accept like
your your input and then the xslt to
transform it with um and so it's one of
those like uh business logic type
languages that like well I'm probably
butchering this for xslt experts um but
it's one of those business logic type
languages that allow you to transform
data kind of arbitrarily in like a user
friendly way like you know somebody who
can write an Excel document can go and
write this XML format um and so
apparently after as I found out like
actually a lot of folks other folks at
the slacking event found s point and
just kind of did a simple like xxt
payload and kind of called it a day um
yep I decided to spend a bunch of extra
hours digging into this classic classic
Sam so what I actually ended up doing
was like I actually went to the function
reference and I S through every function
uh I'm yeah hold up what so so so you
you did you take up like did you somehow
leak the library name and then set up
your own local instance and then hook up
a debugger I mean whoa whoa whoa whoa
whoa uh what did we do
there
yes I think it was open source I think
it was open source so I'm pretty sure I
my own instance of this uh just test it
out um but then like I also I just want
to I just want to highlight how was like
yeah so anyway I thought this was
interesting so I just you know put a
break point on the debug I was like
what many hours in after trying many
different things like like there's there
are a fair number of public exslt
exploits and like they seem to be fairly
patched um so I did so yeah if I recall
correctly I de said in my own instance
and this is like 2019 no this is even
earlier this would have been 2018 or
2017 um and yeah I just through every
function saw what it did and then I
eventually realized that like you could
string like two or three of these
functions together to get like a really
cool
um uh lfi Gadget and I believe I also
had an RC Gadget in there as well yes
you did but I just remember that because
like I was like there were some
limitations around it like it was there
was a couple I don't recall exactly what
the limitation was but like I kept
trying to explain it further and I
couldn't like maybe I couldn't like
pivot to route or something like that
and so I actually gave a presentation
liveing event afterwards like showing
off which is probably where you remember
from and I was like oh yeah you know I'm
like really disappointed in this bug you
know I thought I could take it further
and I I think it was uh doggy G was like
dude like you still got a crit like
yeah chill it out like he just reading
you know arbitrary files from production
on a multi-billion dollar company like
just just accept it move on take the dub
you
know yeah dude uh exsl is a really
interesting thing that I'm looking
forward to diving into a little bit more
when I find um you know like something
that takes it I'm sorry no go go I gonna
say it
um there's like this whole class of like
business logic languages and things that
aren't really ever meant to be exposed
to the internet and when they are
resulted in really scary things and it's
like there have been efforts to lock
these down but like often they weren't
really ever built to be locked down and
so
they're just going to be they're going
to continue to be kind of like a source
of vulnerabilities going forward and you
know I think that that's a great area
for more original research yeah I mean
we even see this with with XML right
like XML is a data markup language like
why does it have this functionality to
like read local files and send HTTP
requests right um so really it is cool
anytime you see the opportunity to do
something like like that where you're
actually parsing some type of code
you know um on the server side big money
there all righty dude that's a wrap that
was a long ass episode filled with some
amazing content it was kind of amazing
I'm not going to lie to go back and like
review over this year and see all the
amazing things we've talked about it was
it was a
blast it's been such an awesome year so
I hope that all this all these little
clips and tidbits and stuff uh you'll be
just playing it over and over on Loop I
know I will I have so many different
notes and awesome learnings to take away
from this yeah man I I actually had
another as we went back through and
relistened for the clips I have a full
notebook uh you know of stuff that I
need to go back and re- research again
so yeah it's been a great year thanks
everyone for listening and we're going
to bring some awesome content as well in
2024 so hope you keep listening I almost
forgot I also want to give a big shout
out to those members of the critical
thinking Discord community that helped
with the selection of the clips for this
awesome Mega episode that's thonet set
47 xss doctor bug luuck beex yug leak
and PJ Stu so thank you guys so much for
all of your help and for going over a
lot of critical thinking content with me
to find the best clips for this
[Music]
episode